<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-28T16:06:59-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tenuous - A Writer’s Blog</title><subtitle>An IT guy, turned amature writer, posting science fiction and fantasy stories for free on the web.</subtitle><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Loathing Las Vegas - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/loathinglvseries/2019/01/26/loathinglasvegas001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loathing Las Vegas - Part 1" /><published>2019-01-26T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/loathinglvseries/2019/01/26/loathinglasvegas001</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/loathinglvseries/2019/01/26/loathinglasvegas001.html">&lt;p&gt;I awoke with a start, covered from head to toe in a cold sweat. My heaving chest began to slow and I sat up in the darkness. Did I have a nightmare? Whatever caused me to awake in such a panic was lost in the haze of consciousness. I couldn’t remember dreaming anything at all…let alone a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head began to clear and my eyes adjusted to the darkness, allowing me to notice a small crack of light peeking through the curtains from across the room. It came back to me in a flash and I remembered where I was. I was in Las Vegas. To be specific, I was in my hotel room at the Tropicana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suddenly became aware of the body next to me, my girlfriend Holly, whose long, deep breaths assured me that my sudden arousal had not woken her too. Since she was sleeping face down, I placed my hand on her back and felt the warmth of her body seep into my cold fingers. She began to slightly stir at the touch, so I pulled my hand away and slowly crept out of bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quietly walked over to the curtains and pulled them open just enough to poke my head through. The sudden intense sunlight stung my eyes and minutes seemed to pass before they were able to refocus. It had been quite a marathon of irresponsible alcohol consumption the night before and my eyes obviously hadn’t fully recovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was daytime in Vegas, the ugly half of the city’s facade, and our room’s 17th floor location facilitated quite a view of the city and the desert beyond. Thousands of people could be seen meandering about the strip below, but traffic on Las Vegas Blvd was surprisingly light. In fact, I couldn’t see any cars on the strip at all. Maybe they closed it down for an event?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind soon wandered and my eyes fell upon a flashing electronic billboard hung above the entrance of the MGM Grand. The sign scrolled, “All-you-can-eat Fried Shrimp and Steak: $8.99”. My stomach rumbled…I could already taste the shrimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reclosed the curtain and stumbled back into the room. Fumbling through my suitcase in the darkness, I somehow managed to properly dress myself and put on my flip-flops. Grabbing my wallet and room key from the night stand, I momentarily considered waking Holly and asking her to join me for breakfast. The mental image of the two of us at breakfast was quickly replaced with the Patron shot glass pyramid she had built the night before and I smartly changed my mind. Maybe in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t exactly escaped hangover free either; I wasn’t feeling sick, but a slightly throbbing headache reminded me that a hundred ounce fruity drink from Fat Tuesday’s costs more than the $30 they advertise it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding to stick with beer for the rest of the day, I grabbed a Heineken from my cooler. I didn’t normally drink first thing in the morning, but clichés of ‘hey I’m on vacation’, ‘this is Vegas baby’ and ‘drinking is the best cure for a hangover’ ran through my mind. I was always good at rationalizing a drunken stupor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened the door and headed down the hallway towards unlimited mounds of shrimp and steak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes and a short elevator ride away, I was on the casino floor. It only took a few steps out of the elevator for me to realize something wasn’t right. I could see plenty of people and the sounds of music and slot machines chimed through the casino. It wasn’t so much that something was out of place as the pace of everything was just off; as if the life has been drained from the casino. No one was cheering, no one was talking. There weren’t any kids hurrying past security guards or middle-aged women screaming into their cell phones. There were no drink waitresses working their way around the machines. In fact, no one was sitting at a machine at all. As if time were stopped, they were all just standing there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all happened in a split second so my mind was reeling to make sense out of the scenario. What the hell was everyone doing? A moment later, I had the answer. What was the one thing every single individual on the casino floor had in common? They were all looking at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a dazed confusion I took a half step back. A short, elderly lady was only about 20 feet away from me and my attention snapped towards her as she began to move towards me. Her red shirt glistened in the light of the well-lit casino and something was hanging from her neck. As she took another step closer, I realized to my horror that her neck had been ripped open and a wad of flesh drooped from it. Her shirt wasn’t red, the sleeves were green; it was stained by the wave of blood that had erupted from her neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I desperately looked around for help. A security guard stumbled around some machines, tripping and falling in front of the old woman. Torn flesh and damaged veins hung from the stump where his arm used to be, but the injury didn’t seem to bother him. He turned his head to look at me and stared at me for a moment with lifeless, glazed-over eyes. His nose wrinkled as if sniffing the air and he bared his teeth at me while emitting a horrible, guttural scream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My eyes began to tear with shock and I stumbled back into the closed elevator doors. The old woman tried to take another step, but the security guard had fallen in her path and she lost her balance, dropping on top of him. They each tried to climb each other in an attempt to get back on their feet, both of them, eyes intently on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I again visually searched the casino for some shred of sanity, but there was no help there. Dozens of people slowly approached me, each with the same dead, glassy look in their eyes. Some were missing arms, some were simply bleeding profusely from wounds. One woman was missing both her legs and was managing to drag herself towards me by her arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a rat trapped in a corner, I frantically searched for an escape route. Before I knew what I was doing, my hand painfully slapped the elevator button and the doors slowly pulled open. I darted inside and pushed the ‘17’ button as quickly as I possibly could. I frantically pummeled the ‘close doors’ button and looked back out towards the casino as the doors began to slowly shut. To my horror, the old woman had apparently managed to regain her footing and was close enough to stick her arm between the closing elevator doors. As soon as the doors detected the object, they swung back open, putting me face to face with an 80 year-old woman who was mashing her teeth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the only object I brought with me, the unopened Heineken bottle, I instinctively smashed the woman on the forehead, sending shards of broken glass and foamy beer across her face. Although a terrible waste of beer, the action had the desired effect, and the force sent the woman tumbling backwards. I repressed the ‘close door’ button and the last thing I saw as the doors slid shut was the woman again rising to her feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slumped to the floor as the sounds of Sinatra filled the elevator. The trip to the 17th floor felt like hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled down the hallway in a frantic attempt to retreat to the safety of my hotel room. My hands were shaking so much it took several attempts to successfully aim the card key into the slot. With a click, the door unlocked and I forced my way into the darkened room, slamming the heavy door shut behind me and locking the deadbolt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinting across the room to the window, I grabbed the curtains and threw them open, filling the room with blinding sunlight. I nearly jumped through window when an angry voice growled from under the covers of the bed, “What the fuck, Kev!?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holly, get up,” the sense of urgency was clear in my tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Close the blinds and give me a minute,” she begged, too hungover to really care what I was in such a hurry for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holly, get up now,” I said sternly while pulling the covers off the bed. “Something fucked-up is going on right now. Get dressed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She curled her naked body into the fetal position and finally lifted her head to look at me, “Assho…” Her anger instantly subsided when she saw the look on my face. That look told her to get the hell out of bed and get dressed. “What’s going on?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was just attacked in the casino. An old lady was bleeding from her neck and I think she was trying to bite me. I smashed my Heineken over her head…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You did what!?!” she yelled as she pulled her shirt on over her head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t just her…a security guard was missing his arm…everyone in the casino had this weird look in their eyes,” I said, stuttering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What the fuck are you talking about?” She pulled on her jeans and walked over to the window, “Christ, you hit an old woman…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both stopped talking as we witnessed the spectacle unfolding on the Las Vegas strip below. A police car raced down the strip, swerving in and out of pedestrians who apparently weren’t restricting themselves to the sidewalk. As the car passed through the Tropicana Blvd intersection, several dozen people flung themselves from the overhead walkway and down onto the street. The officer swerved to avoid the falling bodies, jumped the curb and hit the streetlight head-on with his car. Swirls of smoke poured out from under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly gasped at the sight of the collision, but relaxed when the officer opened his door and stumbled out onto the street. Several of the bridge jumpers had risen to their feet and began to slowly make their way towards the officer. Bystanders surrounding the collision also noticed the commotion and also began approaching the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see the officer yelling something, then he pulled his revolver and began randomly shooting anyone around him. “What the hell is he doing,” Holly cried as a woman took a shot to the head and crumbled to the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn’t hear the shots through the closed hotel window, but we assumed he was out of ammunition when he hurled his gun at the crowd. He had only managed to drop the woman, and his barrage did little to effect the crowd’s determination to reach him. The officer fell to his knees as two men grabbed each of his arms…and ripped them from his body. He fell on his face in a heap as the crowd pounced on top of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly took several steps backward from the window, her eyes wet with tears. She looked at me for some kind of an explanation, but all I could do was turn away from her and look back out the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Kev…what the fuck is going on…did they just kill that cop? Why are people jumping from bridges…why did he shoot those people…” She burst into tears and I grabbed her in my arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” I said, “but I think we need to get the fuck out of here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, Holly calmed down and I sat on the edge of the bed, racking my brain. There was no way in hell I was going back down to that casino, but as far as I knew, that was the only way back to the ground floor. We wouldn’t have anywhere to go anyway…the valet had our car and keys, and somehow I doubted there was anyone working the valet at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly grabbed the hotel room phone and put the receiver to her ear. She hit a few buttons on the keypad and slammed the phone back in place, “It’s dead. My cell phone!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She grabbed her purse from the nightstand and dumped its contents onto the bed. As she flipped open her phone, I used the remote to turn on the TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s no use…I have service, but it just keeps coming up busy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holly,” I said, calmly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe a text message will work…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holly,” I said, firmly this time. She turned at looked at the TV as I flipped from channel to channel, seeing nothing but static. “We have to get the fuck out of here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both frantically searched our bags for anything we could use in a survival situation. I generally preferred to pack light, so other than several fresh changes of clothes, the only other items in my suitcase were a flask, a lighter, a cigar cutter and my four-inch pocket knife, all of which I jammed into my jean’s pockets. Holly, on the other hand, packed practically two weeks of necessities, in two bags, for a mere weekend trip. Unfortunately her dedication to ‘being prepared’ was useless, since having an outfit for any occasion wouldn’t do much against a rabid mob. The only potentially useful item we found was a can of mace from her purse, which she pocketed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keep trying the cell phone,” I knew where I was headed, I just wasn’t sure what I was going to do once I got there. “Maybe we’ll get a better signal from the roof.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we cautiously exited the hotel room, Holly turned left to head toward the elevators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-uh,” I signaled her in my direction as I turned to the right, “I think I’ll take the stairs this time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing my knife from its pocket and opening the blade, I led Holly down the hallway. There were doors on both sides, so I fully expected a bloodthirsty mob to jump out of each one we passed. The hallway was eerily quiet and I got the feeling that we were the only people still on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last door at the end of the hallway had an icon of a staircase painted on it, and I paused as I put my hand on the push bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s wrong?” Holly inquired upon my hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m just trying to decide if opening this door is such a great idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It can’t be any worse than hanging out here in this exposed hallway,” Holly rationalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good point,” I said as I pushed the door open, baring the pocket knife ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stairwell was well-lit and in good condition, but more importantly, it was empty. I wasn’t sure how far it was to the top of the hotel, but I knew from see the hotel outside, that it was at least twenty stories tall. Luckily, our room was already on the 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly closed the door behind her as she entered the stairwell and we both paused for a long moment to listen. Off in the distance we could hear loud thumping and banging. The noises were definitely originating at least several floors below us, but we decided against going down to investigate. We couldn’t hear anything from above our position, so we started to climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staircase leading to the 23rd floor dead-ended at a shut door with sunlight trickling around the edges. Along the push bar of the door was labeled ‘Authorized Personnel Only’, but at this point neither of us were worried about violating hotel policy. I opened the door a crack and peeked through, allowing my eyes to adjust to the sunlight. It was August in the desert, and I could feel the stifling heat pouring through the crack and into the air-conditioned stairwell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s out there?” Holly asked, trying to look past me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this vantage point, I could only see a small portion of the roof, but everything seemed quiet and undisturbed, so I pushed the door open the rest of the way. It swung wide and we both stepped out onto the gravel covered rooftop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as Holly could get past me, she ran over to the ledge closest to the strip. I cautiously followed after her while surveying the roof for any sign of movement. After deciding the roof was clear, I put my knife back in its pocket and joined Holly at the ledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look, the cop is gone,” Holly said, pointing at the blood stained asphalt where he fell. “Where did he go?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glanced around the street, but didn’t see him anywhere. There’s no way he could have walked away with those injuries. The street was still filled with those insane people, so it’s unlikely an ambulance would have been able to get to him without meeting the same fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suddenly blurted out the only possibility I couldn’t eliminate, “Maybe they ate him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly snapped her head back and gave me a look as if she couldn’t believe what had just come out of my mouth. Holly’s brother was a police officer back in California, so I think she took my comment personally. Her eyes welled up and she looked back down at the street, ashamed to admit she was thinking the same thing herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put my arm over her shoulder and visually scanned the area surrounding the hotel. The Excalibur, the castle themed hotel across the street, was on fire and smoke was pouring out of broken windows on several floors. The streets were still full of wandering pedestrians and I could now see quite a few abandoned cars further down the strip. McCarran airport was right behind us and was void of activity; highly unusual for one of the highest volume airports on the planet. Something horrible had happened here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could also hear screaming in the distance, but I couldn’t tell where it was coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the obvious disaster that had befallen the city, Las Vegas still appeared to be in pretty good shape. Electricity was still functioning properly on almost every casino, and, aside from the smoldering Excalibur, everything appeared normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the eerie silence that was getting to me. Vegas was always a town hopped up on alcohol, drugs, sex and excitement. Seeing it like this was like looking at it in a painting or a photo. Sure, it looks exactly the same, but you can’t feel the life or energy of actually being in the middle of it. Well, I was certainly in the middle of it and the only life I felt was the one standing next to me on the ledge of the Tropicana’s roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A metallic bang startled both of us and we looked back at the roof. The stairwell door slowly swung back and forth in the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s ok,” I told Holly who was visibly rattled, “it was just the wind.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blood stained arm reached out of the shadowed stairwell opening and grabbed the edge of the doorway. A bald, middle aged man with glasses poked his head outside and lazily looked around the roof top. His glasses were askew on his face and his white t-shirt was stained red with blood. He froze when he noticed the two of us standing next to the ledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled my knife out and flipped open the blade. We had carelessly left the rooftop door open, giving these monsters full access to our only area of safety. I knew I had to get that door closed before more could make their way through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knife in hand, I ran at the man, who growled and mashed his teeth as I approached. When I was close enough to strike, the man grabbed a hold of my free forearm and squeezed it painfully. I reactively brought the knife down into the top of his skull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His grip on my arm relaxed and he stood there for a moment, as if confused. He then collapsed backward under his own weight, the knife still in his head, and tumbled down the stairwell. On his way down to the next floor, his limp body impacted a group of other blood soaked individuals who were making their way up the stairs. I slammed the rooftop door shut and desperately searched for a way to bar it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the rooftop door had no outer locking mechanism and could easily be opened by a firm push on the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here!” Holly shouted, handing me a section of metal cable she had pulled from the ground. I wrapped the door handle with the cable and tied it to a thick, steel pipe that ran vertically, just around the corner of the rooftop doorway. I looped it around a few extra times, just to make sure it wouldn’t come loose. As I finished, a force impacted the door. The cable held as the monster inside desperately tried to beat down the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, the beating stopped and we decided it must have given up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How’s your arm?” Holly asked, reminding me the intense grip the monster had on my arm. There were no cuts or bleeding, but a nasty bruise did seem eminent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh god, your other arm is bleeding,” Holly gasped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I examined my right arm. It was completely uninjured, but quite a bit of my attacker’s blood had smeared onto me during the knife assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, it’s ok…it’s not my blood,” I said as I wiped as much as I could off with my shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you sure you’re ok? That guy looked like he wanted to bite your head off.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I’m fine,” I assured her, “I’d say he got the worse end of the deal. Anyway, I’m more concerned that we might have just lost our only way off this rooftop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I’m pretty sure I saw another stairwell on the far side of the roof,” Holly said, pointing in the distance to another boxy structure emerging from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We should go tie that one off too or get the hell off of this roof before it’s too late,” She finished, grabbing another length of cable from the remnants left on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which we should do, we began walking towards the other stairwell. Should we dehydrate to death on this roof, under the intense heat of the sun or should we risk getting mauled to death by the occupants of the hotel? Neither seemed a promising choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approached the second stairwell door, it burst open, and five people stumbled into the sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holy shit, I thought I was going to suffocate in that damn thing,” complained a large, portly man wearing a poker themed shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We should be able to…freeze!” the second man, in the uniform of a security guard, interrupted himself as he saw us, raising a pistol. As he did so, the other three members of his group, three women in their twenties, screamed and ran back into the stairwell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both froze in place with our hands up in front of us. We were more relieved to see normal, talking human beings than fearful of having a gun pointed at us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hang on man, we’re not one of them,” I said, dropping my hands. “We thought we were the only normal people left.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security guard relaxed, dropped his pistol and announced, “It’s ok, they’re just more survivors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young women emerged from the doorway and cautiously evaluated us from behind the security guard. One of them had an interesting hat, like a mini-bridal veil, on her head and I assumed they must be in town for a wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m Kevin and this is my girlfriend, Holly,” I said, extending my arm for a hand shake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The name’s Martin,” the security guard said, grasping my hand. When he glanced down and noticed the remaining blood on my arm he alarmingly pulled his arm back and re-aimed his weapon. “Where have you been bitten?!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not a bite,” I responded, nervously, “I stabbed one of those creatures over at the other stairwell and got his blood all over me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin lowered the gun and roughly grabbed my arm, carefully inspecting the area for any injuries. Holly had enough, “What the fuck is your problem? Why are you so worried about a bite anyway?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin, apparently satisfied that I wasn’t injured, holstered his gun and answered Holly, “If one of those things bites you, you eventually turn into one of them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was back when there were six of us,” chimed in the man wearing the poker shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security guard finished the story for him, “An old man was bitten by his wife and found us down on ten. He was in pretty bad shape. He lasted for about twenty minutes before he finally turned.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are these things?” Holly asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin shook his head, “I don’t know, but we have to get out of the city. Bullets don’t even put these things down unless you shoot them in the head. Wil here thinks it’s some kind of virus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What else could it be?” said Wil, the man in the poker shirt. “It’s like some kind of brain eating form of rabies or something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three women standing behind Martin were still visibly shaking. Despite the sweltering heat of the rooftop, they were huddled next to each other as if trying to get warm. It didn’t seem like any of them had taken this disaster very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them finally managed to gather enough courage to yell, “How are we going to get out of here!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m working on it,” Martin replied, as if annoyed. He leaned closer to Holly and myself and whispered, “I haven’t been able to get any of their names, so far. They’ve kind of just been following me since I shot my way out of the casino.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He nodded towards Holly, “Maybe she can talk to them…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly accepted and sat the three women against the ledge wall, while Martin, Wil and I secured the stairwell door and discussed our situation. Wil had been in town for a poker tournament at the Rio, but busted out on the first day. His flight was scheduled to leave later tonight and return to San Diego, where he worked in IT consulting. Martin was a Las Vegas resident and the afternoon security manager for the Tropicana. His wife had recently kicked him out of the house, so he had been staying at the hotel. He woke that morning, ready for work, and walked into the same disaster Holly and I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It took me half a clip,” Martin explained, “before I finally dropped one with a head shot. After that I could bring them down in one shot every time. Had to take out half my department just trying to get back to the elevator.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours passed and we made little progress towards a plan on getting us out of the city. The sun has started to set behind the mountains and everyone was getting hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun had finally set behind the mountain, but Las Vegas wasn’t a city that dulled at night. Whatever disaster that had befallen the city apparently had no effect on the power grid, as neon and LED lights brightened the strip. Even most of the lights on the Excalibur, which was still smoking from various fires, were lit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group sat quietly on the rooftop, unsure of what move to make next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So are we going to wait here for help?” said Wil, breaking the silence. “Or are we going to try to get ourselves out of the city. The airport isn’t very far…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you know how to fly?” asked Martin, the obvious question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” replied Wil, “but I think I’d still prefer a plane crash to getting eaten alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t intended as a joke, but Martin and I couldn’t help bursting out in laughter. Holly, noticing the mood was starting to lighten, waived me over to meet her at the edge of the roof that was out of earshot of the rest of the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what’s going on?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wil’s idea is to make a break for the airport and take our chances trying to fly out of here. He hasn’t said so, but I get the feeling Martin wants to wait here for help and I’m inclined to agree. Considering what I’ve seen so far, I don’t know how we’d have a chance of making it to McCarran.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a pause, I asked, “What’s with the girls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It took me awhile, but they’ve finally calmed down,” Holly explained, “I guess the three of them are from California, too. Sheri, the one with the bridal hat, is getting married next week and the three of them drove out here for a bachelorette trip. I think it’s a safe bet that they’ll follow whatever the group wants to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How’s your arm?” Holly added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sore, but I’ll survive,” I said with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please do,” she replied, warmly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later the group met back up near the strip side of the rooftop. Wil was pretty adamant about his plan to make it to the airport, but quickly changed his mind when Martin showed him the two remaining rounds left in his pistol. We were all in agreement that we’d need more than two bullets to make it to McCarran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have an armory down in the security offices,” Martin explained, “but I was barely able to get out of there the last time. There’s enough rifles, shotguns and riot gear down there for a small army, if we could get to it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s it,” Wil said, excitedly. “We’ll go down, get the guns and fight our way to the airport.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It sounds risky,” I said to Martin, “but I’d say it’s the best plan we have. There isn’t any food or water up here and it’s the middle of summer. We won’t last more than a few more days up here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin seemed to come around, “Alright, but we’re going to need to come up with something to get into those offices. I’m telling you, the place was crawling with those fuckers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls seemed nervous about the plan, but everyone eventually agreed that there was no other reasonable option. We decided to make the attempt first thing in the morning after everyone had a chance to rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peaceful silence of the early morning was broken by the sound of approaching aircraft. The noise jolted me from an uneasy sleep and I wiped the gravel from my clothing as I stood. Martin was already awake and standing at the rooftop ledge, looking into the distance towards the sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a military chopper,” he said calmly as he heard me approach. “It’s sweeping the city like it’s looking for something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the distance, a black helicopter slowly made its way, back and forth, over the city. The rest of the group had awakened and joined us at the ledge. The three girls from the bachelorette party fruitlessly waived their arms in the air, trying to get the chopper’s attention. No one had the heart to tell them they were much too far away to be noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s been making his way towards the center of the city all morning,” said Martin, “he should be right over us within an hour.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank god,” said one of the three women who all began to excitedly hug each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked over at Wil, “Looks like you won’t be earning your pilot’s license today.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wil nodded and smiled back. He didn’t look disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as the sun cleared the edge of the eastern mountains, the helicopter began to make its way down the northern end of the strip. As it approached us, we could hear the sound of a muffled loud speaker booming down the corridor created by the hotels. It was almost right above us before we could understand the message it was broadcasting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Attention survivors: please rendezvous with rescuers at the rooftop of the Bellagio. The Bellagio has the only rooftop helicopter pad in the city. We will not land at any other point. Make your way to the Bellagio rooftop within 72 hours for airlift rescue.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message continuously repeated as the chopper flew past us and continued down the strip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin pulled his pistol from its holster, loaded a bullet into the chamber and said, “Alright everyone, let’s move.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">I awoke with a start, covered from head to toe in a cold sweat. My heaving chest began to slow and I sat up in the darkness. Did I have a nightmare? Whatever caused me to awake in such a panic was lost in the haze of consciousness. I couldn’t remember dreaming anything at all…let alone a nightmare. My head began to clear and my eyes adjusted to the darkness, allowing me to notice a small crack of light peeking through the curtains from across the room. It came back to me in a flash and I remembered where I was. I was in Las Vegas. To be specific, I was in my hotel room at the Tropicana. I suddenly became aware of the body next to me, my girlfriend Holly, whose long, deep breaths assured me that my sudden arousal had not woken her too. Since she was sleeping face down, I placed my hand on her back and felt the warmth of her body seep into my cold fingers. She began to slightly stir at the touch, so I pulled my hand away and slowly crept out of bed. I quietly walked over to the curtains and pulled them open just enough to poke my head through. The sudden intense sunlight stung my eyes and minutes seemed to pass before they were able to refocus. It had been quite a marathon of irresponsible alcohol consumption the night before and my eyes obviously hadn’t fully recovered. It was daytime in Vegas, the ugly half of the city’s facade, and our room’s 17th floor location facilitated quite a view of the city and the desert beyond. Thousands of people could be seen meandering about the strip below, but traffic on Las Vegas Blvd was surprisingly light. In fact, I couldn’t see any cars on the strip at all. Maybe they closed it down for an event? My mind soon wandered and my eyes fell upon a flashing electronic billboard hung above the entrance of the MGM Grand. The sign scrolled, “All-you-can-eat Fried Shrimp and Steak: $8.99”. My stomach rumbled…I could already taste the shrimp. I reclosed the curtain and stumbled back into the room. Fumbling through my suitcase in the darkness, I somehow managed to properly dress myself and put on my flip-flops. Grabbing my wallet and room key from the night stand, I momentarily considered waking Holly and asking her to join me for breakfast. The mental image of the two of us at breakfast was quickly replaced with the Patron shot glass pyramid she had built the night before and I smartly changed my mind. Maybe in a few hours. I hadn’t exactly escaped hangover free either; I wasn’t feeling sick, but a slightly throbbing headache reminded me that a hundred ounce fruity drink from Fat Tuesday’s costs more than the $30 they advertise it for. Deciding to stick with beer for the rest of the day, I grabbed a Heineken from my cooler. I didn’t normally drink first thing in the morning, but clichés of ‘hey I’m on vacation’, ‘this is Vegas baby’ and ‘drinking is the best cure for a hangover’ ran through my mind. I was always good at rationalizing a drunken stupor. I opened the door and headed down the hallway towards unlimited mounds of shrimp and steak. A few minutes and a short elevator ride away, I was on the casino floor. It only took a few steps out of the elevator for me to realize something wasn’t right. I could see plenty of people and the sounds of music and slot machines chimed through the casino. It wasn’t so much that something was out of place as the pace of everything was just off; as if the life has been drained from the casino. No one was cheering, no one was talking. There weren’t any kids hurrying past security guards or middle-aged women screaming into their cell phones. There were no drink waitresses working their way around the machines. In fact, no one was sitting at a machine at all. As if time were stopped, they were all just standing there. This all happened in a split second so my mind was reeling to make sense out of the scenario. What the hell was everyone doing? A moment later, I had the answer. What was the one thing every single individual on the casino floor had in common? They were all looking at me. In a dazed confusion I took a half step back. A short, elderly lady was only about 20 feet away from me and my attention snapped towards her as she began to move towards me. Her red shirt glistened in the light of the well-lit casino and something was hanging from her neck. As she took another step closer, I realized to my horror that her neck had been ripped open and a wad of flesh drooped from it. Her shirt wasn’t red, the sleeves were green; it was stained by the wave of blood that had erupted from her neck. I desperately looked around for help. A security guard stumbled around some machines, tripping and falling in front of the old woman. Torn flesh and damaged veins hung from the stump where his arm used to be, but the injury didn’t seem to bother him. He turned his head to look at me and stared at me for a moment with lifeless, glazed-over eyes. His nose wrinkled as if sniffing the air and he bared his teeth at me while emitting a horrible, guttural scream. My eyes began to tear with shock and I stumbled back into the closed elevator doors. The old woman tried to take another step, but the security guard had fallen in her path and she lost her balance, dropping on top of him. They each tried to climb each other in an attempt to get back on their feet, both of them, eyes intently on me. I again visually searched the casino for some shred of sanity, but there was no help there. Dozens of people slowly approached me, each with the same dead, glassy look in their eyes. Some were missing arms, some were simply bleeding profusely from wounds. One woman was missing both her legs and was managing to drag herself towards me by her arms. Like a rat trapped in a corner, I frantically searched for an escape route. Before I knew what I was doing, my hand painfully slapped the elevator button and the doors slowly pulled open. I darted inside and pushed the ‘17’ button as quickly as I possibly could. I frantically pummeled the ‘close doors’ button and looked back out towards the casino as the doors began to slowly shut. To my horror, the old woman had apparently managed to regain her footing and was close enough to stick her arm between the closing elevator doors. As soon as the doors detected the object, they swung back open, putting me face to face with an 80 year-old woman who was mashing her teeth. Using the only object I brought with me, the unopened Heineken bottle, I instinctively smashed the woman on the forehead, sending shards of broken glass and foamy beer across her face. Although a terrible waste of beer, the action had the desired effect, and the force sent the woman tumbling backwards. I repressed the ‘close door’ button and the last thing I saw as the doors slid shut was the woman again rising to her feet. I slumped to the floor as the sounds of Sinatra filled the elevator. The trip to the 17th floor felt like hours. I stumbled down the hallway in a frantic attempt to retreat to the safety of my hotel room. My hands were shaking so much it took several attempts to successfully aim the card key into the slot. With a click, the door unlocked and I forced my way into the darkened room, slamming the heavy door shut behind me and locking the deadbolt. Sprinting across the room to the window, I grabbed the curtains and threw them open, filling the room with blinding sunlight. I nearly jumped through window when an angry voice growled from under the covers of the bed, “What the fuck, Kev!?” “Holly, get up,” the sense of urgency was clear in my tone. “Close the blinds and give me a minute,” she begged, too hungover to really care what I was in such a hurry for. “Holly, get up now,” I said sternly while pulling the covers off the bed. “Something fucked-up is going on right now. Get dressed.” She curled her naked body into the fetal position and finally lifted her head to look at me, “Assho…” Her anger instantly subsided when she saw the look on my face. That look told her to get the hell out of bed and get dressed. “What’s going on?” “I was just attacked in the casino. An old lady was bleeding from her neck and I think she was trying to bite me. I smashed my Heineken over her head…” “You did what!?!” she yelled as she pulled her shirt on over her head. “It wasn’t just her…a security guard was missing his arm…everyone in the casino had this weird look in their eyes,” I said, stuttering. “What the fuck are you talking about?” She pulled on her jeans and walked over to the window, “Christ, you hit an old woman…” We both stopped talking as we witnessed the spectacle unfolding on the Las Vegas strip below. A police car raced down the strip, swerving in and out of pedestrians who apparently weren’t restricting themselves to the sidewalk. As the car passed through the Tropicana Blvd intersection, several dozen people flung themselves from the overhead walkway and down onto the street. The officer swerved to avoid the falling bodies, jumped the curb and hit the streetlight head-on with his car. Swirls of smoke poured out from under the hood. Holly gasped at the sight of the collision, but relaxed when the officer opened his door and stumbled out onto the street. Several of the bridge jumpers had risen to their feet and began to slowly make their way towards the officer. Bystanders surrounding the collision also noticed the commotion and also began approaching the scene. We could see the officer yelling something, then he pulled his revolver and began randomly shooting anyone around him. “What the hell is he doing,” Holly cried as a woman took a shot to the head and crumbled to the pavement. We couldn’t hear the shots through the closed hotel window, but we assumed he was out of ammunition when he hurled his gun at the crowd. He had only managed to drop the woman, and his barrage did little to effect the crowd’s determination to reach him. The officer fell to his knees as two men grabbed each of his arms…and ripped them from his body. He fell on his face in a heap as the crowd pounced on top of him. Holly took several steps backward from the window, her eyes wet with tears. She looked at me for some kind of an explanation, but all I could do was turn away from her and look back out the window. “Kev…what the fuck is going on…did they just kill that cop? Why are people jumping from bridges…why did he shoot those people…” She burst into tears and I grabbed her in my arms. “I don’t know,” I said, “but I think we need to get the fuck out of here.” After a few minutes, Holly calmed down and I sat on the edge of the bed, racking my brain. There was no way in hell I was going back down to that casino, but as far as I knew, that was the only way back to the ground floor. We wouldn’t have anywhere to go anyway…the valet had our car and keys, and somehow I doubted there was anyone working the valet at that moment. Holly grabbed the hotel room phone and put the receiver to her ear. She hit a few buttons on the keypad and slammed the phone back in place, “It’s dead. My cell phone!” She grabbed her purse from the nightstand and dumped its contents onto the bed. As she flipped open her phone, I used the remote to turn on the TV. “It’s no use…I have service, but it just keeps coming up busy.” “Holly,” I said, calmly. “Maybe a text message will work…” “Holly,” I said, firmly this time. She turned at looked at the TV as I flipped from channel to channel, seeing nothing but static. “We have to get the fuck out of here.” We both frantically searched our bags for anything we could use in a survival situation. I generally preferred to pack light, so other than several fresh changes of clothes, the only other items in my suitcase were a flask, a lighter, a cigar cutter and my four-inch pocket knife, all of which I jammed into my jean’s pockets. Holly, on the other hand, packed practically two weeks of necessities, in two bags, for a mere weekend trip. Unfortunately her dedication to ‘being prepared’ was useless, since having an outfit for any occasion wouldn’t do much against a rabid mob. The only potentially useful item we found was a can of mace from her purse, which she pocketed. “Keep trying the cell phone,” I knew where I was headed, I just wasn’t sure what I was going to do once I got there. “Maybe we’ll get a better signal from the roof.” As we cautiously exited the hotel room, Holly turned left to head toward the elevators. “Uh-uh,” I signaled her in my direction as I turned to the right, “I think I’ll take the stairs this time.” Removing my knife from its pocket and opening the blade, I led Holly down the hallway. There were doors on both sides, so I fully expected a bloodthirsty mob to jump out of each one we passed. The hallway was eerily quiet and I got the feeling that we were the only people still on the floor. The last door at the end of the hallway had an icon of a staircase painted on it, and I paused as I put my hand on the push bar. “What’s wrong?” Holly inquired upon my hesitation. “I’m just trying to decide if opening this door is such a great idea.” “It can’t be any worse than hanging out here in this exposed hallway,” Holly rationalized. “Good point,” I said as I pushed the door open, baring the pocket knife ahead of me. The stairwell was well-lit and in good condition, but more importantly, it was empty. I wasn’t sure how far it was to the top of the hotel, but I knew from see the hotel outside, that it was at least twenty stories tall. Luckily, our room was already on the 17th. Holly closed the door behind her as she entered the stairwell and we both paused for a long moment to listen. Off in the distance we could hear loud thumping and banging. The noises were definitely originating at least several floors below us, but we decided against going down to investigate. We couldn’t hear anything from above our position, so we started to climb. The staircase leading to the 23rd floor dead-ended at a shut door with sunlight trickling around the edges. Along the push bar of the door was labeled ‘Authorized Personnel Only’, but at this point neither of us were worried about violating hotel policy. I opened the door a crack and peeked through, allowing my eyes to adjust to the sunlight. It was August in the desert, and I could feel the stifling heat pouring through the crack and into the air-conditioned stairwell. “What’s out there?” Holly asked, trying to look past me. From this vantage point, I could only see a small portion of the roof, but everything seemed quiet and undisturbed, so I pushed the door open the rest of the way. It swung wide and we both stepped out onto the gravel covered rooftop. As soon as Holly could get past me, she ran over to the ledge closest to the strip. I cautiously followed after her while surveying the roof for any sign of movement. After deciding the roof was clear, I put my knife back in its pocket and joined Holly at the ledge. “Look, the cop is gone,” Holly said, pointing at the blood stained asphalt where he fell. “Where did he go?” I glanced around the street, but didn’t see him anywhere. There’s no way he could have walked away with those injuries. The street was still filled with those insane people, so it’s unlikely an ambulance would have been able to get to him without meeting the same fate. I suddenly blurted out the only possibility I couldn’t eliminate, “Maybe they ate him?” Holly snapped her head back and gave me a look as if she couldn’t believe what had just come out of my mouth. Holly’s brother was a police officer back in California, so I think she took my comment personally. Her eyes welled up and she looked back down at the street, ashamed to admit she was thinking the same thing herself. I put my arm over her shoulder and visually scanned the area surrounding the hotel. The Excalibur, the castle themed hotel across the street, was on fire and smoke was pouring out of broken windows on several floors. The streets were still full of wandering pedestrians and I could now see quite a few abandoned cars further down the strip. McCarran airport was right behind us and was void of activity; highly unusual for one of the highest volume airports on the planet. Something horrible had happened here. I could also hear screaming in the distance, but I couldn’t tell where it was coming from. Despite the obvious disaster that had befallen the city, Las Vegas still appeared to be in pretty good shape. Electricity was still functioning properly on almost every casino, and, aside from the smoldering Excalibur, everything appeared normal. It was the eerie silence that was getting to me. Vegas was always a town hopped up on alcohol, drugs, sex and excitement. Seeing it like this was like looking at it in a painting or a photo. Sure, it looks exactly the same, but you can’t feel the life or energy of actually being in the middle of it. Well, I was certainly in the middle of it and the only life I felt was the one standing next to me on the ledge of the Tropicana’s roof. A metallic bang startled both of us and we looked back at the roof. The stairwell door slowly swung back and forth in the breeze. “It’s ok,” I told Holly who was visibly rattled, “it was just the wind.” A blood stained arm reached out of the shadowed stairwell opening and grabbed the edge of the doorway. A bald, middle aged man with glasses poked his head outside and lazily looked around the roof top. His glasses were askew on his face and his white t-shirt was stained red with blood. He froze when he noticed the two of us standing next to the ledge. I pulled my knife out and flipped open the blade. We had carelessly left the rooftop door open, giving these monsters full access to our only area of safety. I knew I had to get that door closed before more could make their way through. Knife in hand, I ran at the man, who growled and mashed his teeth as I approached. When I was close enough to strike, the man grabbed a hold of my free forearm and squeezed it painfully. I reactively brought the knife down into the top of his skull. His grip on my arm relaxed and he stood there for a moment, as if confused. He then collapsed backward under his own weight, the knife still in his head, and tumbled down the stairwell. On his way down to the next floor, his limp body impacted a group of other blood soaked individuals who were making their way up the stairs. I slammed the rooftop door shut and desperately searched for a way to bar it. Unfortunately, the rooftop door had no outer locking mechanism and could easily be opened by a firm push on the door. “Here!” Holly shouted, handing me a section of metal cable she had pulled from the ground. I wrapped the door handle with the cable and tied it to a thick, steel pipe that ran vertically, just around the corner of the rooftop doorway. I looped it around a few extra times, just to make sure it wouldn’t come loose. As I finished, a force impacted the door. The cable held as the monster inside desperately tried to beat down the door. After a few minutes, the beating stopped and we decided it must have given up. “How’s your arm?” Holly asked, reminding me the intense grip the monster had on my arm. There were no cuts or bleeding, but a nasty bruise did seem eminent. “Oh god, your other arm is bleeding,” Holly gasped. I examined my right arm. It was completely uninjured, but quite a bit of my attacker’s blood had smeared onto me during the knife assault. “No, it’s ok…it’s not my blood,” I said as I wiped as much as I could off with my shirt. “Are you sure you’re ok? That guy looked like he wanted to bite your head off.” “Yeah, I’m fine,” I assured her, “I’d say he got the worse end of the deal. Anyway, I’m more concerned that we might have just lost our only way off this rooftop.” “No, I’m pretty sure I saw another stairwell on the far side of the roof,” Holly said, pointing in the distance to another boxy structure emerging from the ground. “We should go tie that one off too or get the hell off of this roof before it’s too late,” She finished, grabbing another length of cable from the remnants left on the ground. Not sure which we should do, we began walking towards the other stairwell. Should we dehydrate to death on this roof, under the intense heat of the sun or should we risk getting mauled to death by the occupants of the hotel? Neither seemed a promising choice. As we approached the second stairwell door, it burst open, and five people stumbled into the sunlight. “Holy shit, I thought I was going to suffocate in that damn thing,” complained a large, portly man wearing a poker themed shirt. “We should be able to…freeze!” the second man, in the uniform of a security guard, interrupted himself as he saw us, raising a pistol. As he did so, the other three members of his group, three women in their twenties, screamed and ran back into the stairwell. We both froze in place with our hands up in front of us. We were more relieved to see normal, talking human beings than fearful of having a gun pointed at us. “Hang on man, we’re not one of them,” I said, dropping my hands. “We thought we were the only normal people left.” The security guard relaxed, dropped his pistol and announced, “It’s ok, they’re just more survivors.” The young women emerged from the doorway and cautiously evaluated us from behind the security guard. One of them had an interesting hat, like a mini-bridal veil, on her head and I assumed they must be in town for a wedding. “I’m Kevin and this is my girlfriend, Holly,” I said, extending my arm for a hand shake. “The name’s Martin,” the security guard said, grasping my hand. When he glanced down and noticed the remaining blood on my arm he alarmingly pulled his arm back and re-aimed his weapon. “Where have you been bitten?!” “It’s not a bite,” I responded, nervously, “I stabbed one of those creatures over at the other stairwell and got his blood all over me.” Martin lowered the gun and roughly grabbed my arm, carefully inspecting the area for any injuries. Holly had enough, “What the fuck is your problem? Why are you so worried about a bite anyway?” Martin, apparently satisfied that I wasn’t injured, holstered his gun and answered Holly, “If one of those things bites you, you eventually turn into one of them.” “That was back when there were six of us,” chimed in the man wearing the poker shirt. The security guard finished the story for him, “An old man was bitten by his wife and found us down on ten. He was in pretty bad shape. He lasted for about twenty minutes before he finally turned.” “What are these things?” Holly asked. Martin shook his head, “I don’t know, but we have to get out of the city. Bullets don’t even put these things down unless you shoot them in the head. Wil here thinks it’s some kind of virus.” “What else could it be?” said Wil, the man in the poker shirt. “It’s like some kind of brain eating form of rabies or something.” The three women standing behind Martin were still visibly shaking. Despite the sweltering heat of the rooftop, they were huddled next to each other as if trying to get warm. It didn’t seem like any of them had taken this disaster very well. One of them finally managed to gather enough courage to yell, “How are we going to get out of here!” “I’m working on it,” Martin replied, as if annoyed. He leaned closer to Holly and myself and whispered, “I haven’t been able to get any of their names, so far. They’ve kind of just been following me since I shot my way out of the casino.” He nodded towards Holly, “Maybe she can talk to them…” Holly accepted and sat the three women against the ledge wall, while Martin, Wil and I secured the stairwell door and discussed our situation. Wil had been in town for a poker tournament at the Rio, but busted out on the first day. His flight was scheduled to leave later tonight and return to San Diego, where he worked in IT consulting. Martin was a Las Vegas resident and the afternoon security manager for the Tropicana. His wife had recently kicked him out of the house, so he had been staying at the hotel. He woke that morning, ready for work, and walked into the same disaster Holly and I had. “It took me half a clip,” Martin explained, “before I finally dropped one with a head shot. After that I could bring them down in one shot every time. Had to take out half my department just trying to get back to the elevator.” Hours passed and we made little progress towards a plan on getting us out of the city. The sun has started to set behind the mountains and everyone was getting hungry. The sun had finally set behind the mountain, but Las Vegas wasn’t a city that dulled at night. Whatever disaster that had befallen the city apparently had no effect on the power grid, as neon and LED lights brightened the strip. Even most of the lights on the Excalibur, which was still smoking from various fires, were lit. The group sat quietly on the rooftop, unsure of what move to make next. “So are we going to wait here for help?” said Wil, breaking the silence. “Or are we going to try to get ourselves out of the city. The airport isn’t very far…” “Do you know how to fly?” asked Martin, the obvious question. “No,” replied Wil, “but I think I’d still prefer a plane crash to getting eaten alive.” It wasn’t intended as a joke, but Martin and I couldn’t help bursting out in laughter. Holly, noticing the mood was starting to lighten, waived me over to meet her at the edge of the roof that was out of earshot of the rest of the group. “So what’s going on?” she asked. “Wil’s idea is to make a break for the airport and take our chances trying to fly out of here. He hasn’t said so, but I get the feeling Martin wants to wait here for help and I’m inclined to agree. Considering what I’ve seen so far, I don’t know how we’d have a chance of making it to McCarran.” After a pause, I asked, “What’s with the girls?” “It took me awhile, but they’ve finally calmed down,” Holly explained, “I guess the three of them are from California, too. Sheri, the one with the bridal hat, is getting married next week and the three of them drove out here for a bachelorette trip. I think it’s a safe bet that they’ll follow whatever the group wants to do.” “How’s your arm?” Holly added. “Sore, but I’ll survive,” I said with a smile. “Please do,” she replied, warmly. A few minutes later the group met back up near the strip side of the rooftop. Wil was pretty adamant about his plan to make it to the airport, but quickly changed his mind when Martin showed him the two remaining rounds left in his pistol. We were all in agreement that we’d need more than two bullets to make it to McCarran. “We have an armory down in the security offices,” Martin explained, “but I was barely able to get out of there the last time. There’s enough rifles, shotguns and riot gear down there for a small army, if we could get to it.” “That’s it,” Wil said, excitedly. “We’ll go down, get the guns and fight our way to the airport.” “It sounds risky,” I said to Martin, “but I’d say it’s the best plan we have. There isn’t any food or water up here and it’s the middle of summer. We won’t last more than a few more days up here.” Martin seemed to come around, “Alright, but we’re going to need to come up with something to get into those offices. I’m telling you, the place was crawling with those fuckers.” The girls seemed nervous about the plan, but everyone eventually agreed that there was no other reasonable option. We decided to make the attempt first thing in the morning after everyone had a chance to rest. … The peaceful silence of the early morning was broken by the sound of approaching aircraft. The noise jolted me from an uneasy sleep and I wiped the gravel from my clothing as I stood. Martin was already awake and standing at the rooftop ledge, looking into the distance towards the sound. “It’s a military chopper,” he said calmly as he heard me approach. “It’s sweeping the city like it’s looking for something.” In the distance, a black helicopter slowly made its way, back and forth, over the city. The rest of the group had awakened and joined us at the ledge. The three girls from the bachelorette party fruitlessly waived their arms in the air, trying to get the chopper’s attention. No one had the heart to tell them they were much too far away to be noticed. “He’s been making his way towards the center of the city all morning,” said Martin, “he should be right over us within an hour.” “Thank god,” said one of the three women who all began to excitedly hug each other. I looked over at Wil, “Looks like you won’t be earning your pilot’s license today.” Wil nodded and smiled back. He didn’t look disappointed. … Just as the sun cleared the edge of the eastern mountains, the helicopter began to make its way down the northern end of the strip. As it approached us, we could hear the sound of a muffled loud speaker booming down the corridor created by the hotels. It was almost right above us before we could understand the message it was broadcasting: “Attention survivors: please rendezvous with rescuers at the rooftop of the Bellagio. The Bellagio has the only rooftop helicopter pad in the city. We will not land at any other point. Make your way to the Bellagio rooftop within 72 hours for airlift rescue.” The message continuously repeated as the chopper flew past us and continued down the strip. Martin pulled his pistol from its holster, loaded a bullet into the chamber and said, “Alright everyone, let’s move.” To be continued…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Observations After 3 Months of the Ketogenic Diet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/health/2019/01/22/ketoobservations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Observations After 3 Months of the Ketogenic Diet" /><published>2019-01-22T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-22T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/health/2019/01/22/ketoobservations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/health/2019/01/22/ketoobservations.html">&lt;p&gt;Fad diets really annoy me. I hate it when people jump into new habits without understanding how things work, or what goals they have in mind. For instance, when the Atkins diet first became popular, I thought the idea that consuming nothing but meat was silly concept. And it was silly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard about the ‘keto’ diet around a year ago, and initially had the same knee-jerk reaction. Here we go again with another fad diet. However, having dealt with several activity and posture related injuries, I’ve taken quite a bit of interest in how diet can impact inflammation. So what did I do? I did what any other red-blooded American would do (hehe), and spent the next year learning about the ketogenic process, and the best-practices of the diet. I even went so far to look up and read through the actual peer-reviewed studies on keto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the keto diet takes all the good things of Atkins, and finds the healthy middle ground between zero-carb and high-protein. The best way to describe keto would be low-carb, moderate-protein, and high-fat. Isn’t fat bad for you, you say? Well, it depends. Without getting into an entire novel of details and explaining the science behind keto, fats are great for you, as long as you’re considering two main factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factor 1:  Sugar.&lt;/strong&gt; A high-sugar, high-fat diet is pretty much the worst diet you can eat. This is what is known as ‘the standard American diet’. This explains our ridiculous obesity, heart disease, and diabetes rates. One of the jobs of fats (or cholesterol) is to repair damage to your circulatory system, kind of like how your skin scabs up when cut. Fats clog your arteries because they are getting damaged by sugars. Fats aren’t causing the damage, but they can kill you when damage is being done. Sugar is horrible for you, in basically any amount, and you should cut it out of your diet. There are essential proteins, essential fats, but no essential sugars. You don’t need sugar to live or be healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factor 2:  Good fats.&lt;/strong&gt; Not all fats are created equal. The good oils are avocado, coconut, and olive. You want to avoid vegetable oil completely. Butter is great for you too, but stick to grass-fed options, where the good life and nutrition of the cow, from a life of eating fresh grass (rather than corn or grain) is jam packed into a single stick of butter. Same with cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what do I eat?&lt;/strong&gt; The diagram below was the best visual aid I could find; however, I tend to put much less emphasis on meats, and more on avocados and eggs. Shrimp shouldn’t be on this chart either…that stuff is garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ketofoodpyramid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most days, I’ll only have two meals, lunch and dinner, with one meal being meatless. My lunch typically consists of a cruciferous salad (kale, broccoli, cabbage, brussel sprouts), topped with hard boiled eggs, feta cheese, and avocado. For salad dressing, I make my own by simply combining a tablespoon of avocado oil and a tablespoon of rice wine vinegar. Luckily, Trader Joes sells the salad mix pre-made, so that saves a lot of prep time. For dinner, I’ll have a variety of options, from pork chops, to beef and broccoli, to cauliflower pizza, to taco bowls. I also grow my own broccoli sprouts in mason jars and top pretty much everything with those bitches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your research. There are a ton of recipe books and information online about keto now, so find out what foods you can and cannot eat, and experiment. It’s not that big a deal if you don’t stick 100% to keto…removing sugars from your diet is a huge improvement on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KETO PRO-TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to save some money on your meats, buy chicken or beef that is lean. Then cook your proteins in good fat sources, like grass-fed butter. This is also a great option if you’re not sure about your meat quality too…when in doubt, get the leaner cuts and add your own fats during cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have I observed after three months?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Bloating is gone.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you wake up in the morning, look at yourself in the mirror, and look pretty good? Then by the end of the day you look fatter, and ‘bloated’ compared to the morning? I used to too! This is due to bloating. Since I started keto, I no longer retain a significant amount of water weight, and I look the same in the mirror all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) I’m a light-weight drinker.&lt;/strong&gt; I can only drink about half of what I used to be able to before getting a buzz. Hangovers are much worse too. This is a common keto observation. This could be attributed to Observation #1, since your hydration levels are a big part of how alcohol affects you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Maintaining weight is automatic.&lt;/strong&gt; Prior to keto, I really had to manage my calories to stay around 170 lbs. Whenever I would get down to this weight, I’d be super hungry all the time, and would bounce back up to 180 over 2-3 months. I’d manage my weight by going through 3 month cycles of cuts and gains, so I didn’t constantly need to track calories. Since I’ve started keto, I’ve stayed stable at 170 without counting calories, and I’m rarely hungry shortly after meals. When I’m hungry, I eat. Never in my life have I been able to do this, and now nearing the ripe old age of 40, that’s quite a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Losing weight is far easier.&lt;/strong&gt; Following from the prior observation, if I wanted to lose additional weight, I could do so quite easily by cutting out a snack here and there, or removing alcohol completely. Back when I used to go through cutting cycles, I’d spend all day looking forward to my next feeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Meals are more fulfilling.&lt;/strong&gt; Try this experiment: For lunch, make five scrambled eggs, and a pack of (quality) bacon. Cook the eggs in a tablespoon of grass-fed butter. Eat all the eggs, and as many bacon strips as you want until you’re full. Now, see how many hours go by until you’re starving again. I bet you either don’t eat dinner, or have a light meal. You see, fats and proteins &lt;strong&gt;help&lt;/strong&gt; you lose weight, because you can easily sustain a diet where you’re rarely hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) I still crave sweets.&lt;/strong&gt; From time-to-time genetics and almost 40 years of bad-behaviors nag at me, and I want something sweet. I never eat sugary junk though, I learned to make keto cookies and peanut butter fat bombs. Other sweet-tooth satisfying options include: spoonful of peanut butter, small handful of dark chocolate, and keto friendly bars (i.e. Quest bars). Note, almost all protein bars aren’t good if you really want to stay in ketosis, so try to avoid them if you can, but they’re still decent options for quick snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) I’ve seen a slight drop-off at the gym.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m on a strength-training focus right now (many sets, few reps), but I did notice a drop-off in progress once I switched to keto. That being said, the drop-off was only slight, and I’m still making good progress. There could also be other factors at play here too, such as hydration levels, age, progress naturally slows at higher weights, etc. I’ve heard other keto dieters observe this too, so something to keep in mind. I don’t do any pre-workout supplements, so that may be an option to mitigate the diet change too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) My digestive system is less predictable.&lt;/strong&gt; Even three months later, I’m still going through various cycles of regularity and irregularity. I most certainly ‘go less’. Days where I feel uncomfortable get fewer and fewer as time goes on though, and as my gut microbiome adjusts to a new way of doing things. I’ve heard this can take months or even as long as a year to adjust, so I’m giving it time. I’ve also consciously added pro-biotic foods to my diet, such as sauerkraut and an occasional kombucha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) Less inflammation? I’m not sure.&lt;/strong&gt; The lack of water retention would suggest my inflammation levels have dropped, but if I’m being honest, I can’t say for sure. I still have join aches and pains here and there, but the frequency and severity of these seems to have diminished. The changes aren’t super dramatic, so I can’t say for sure if this is due to the diet, or other factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) Keto flu wasn’t severe.&lt;/strong&gt; My previous diet was far from keto, but I had been eating healthy foods (salads, eggs, avocado) for awhile. I never ate fast-food and rarely sugary stuff like cookies or soda. Bread and rice were probably my big carb contributors. I think because of this, I missed most of the “keto flu” symptoms that many people report. Other than some constipation, I’m not sure I had any significant symptoms I would classify in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. Hopefully this will help you with your own health decisions. It can’t hurt to try it for a few months and see if it works for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Fad diets really annoy me. I hate it when people jump into new habits without understanding how things work, or what goals they have in mind. For instance, when the Atkins diet first became popular, I thought the idea that consuming nothing but meat was silly concept. And it was silly. I first heard about the ‘keto’ diet around a year ago, and initially had the same knee-jerk reaction. Here we go again with another fad diet. However, having dealt with several activity and posture related injuries, I’ve taken quite a bit of interest in how diet can impact inflammation. So what did I do? I did what any other red-blooded American would do (hehe), and spent the next year learning about the ketogenic process, and the best-practices of the diet. I even went so far to look up and read through the actual peer-reviewed studies on keto. In a nutshell, the keto diet takes all the good things of Atkins, and finds the healthy middle ground between zero-carb and high-protein. The best way to describe keto would be low-carb, moderate-protein, and high-fat. Isn’t fat bad for you, you say? Well, it depends. Without getting into an entire novel of details and explaining the science behind keto, fats are great for you, as long as you’re considering two main factors: Factor 1: Sugar. A high-sugar, high-fat diet is pretty much the worst diet you can eat. This is what is known as ‘the standard American diet’. This explains our ridiculous obesity, heart disease, and diabetes rates. One of the jobs of fats (or cholesterol) is to repair damage to your circulatory system, kind of like how your skin scabs up when cut. Fats clog your arteries because they are getting damaged by sugars. Fats aren’t causing the damage, but they can kill you when damage is being done. Sugar is horrible for you, in basically any amount, and you should cut it out of your diet. There are essential proteins, essential fats, but no essential sugars. You don’t need sugar to live or be healthy. Factor 2: Good fats. Not all fats are created equal. The good oils are avocado, coconut, and olive. You want to avoid vegetable oil completely. Butter is great for you too, but stick to grass-fed options, where the good life and nutrition of the cow, from a life of eating fresh grass (rather than corn or grain) is jam packed into a single stick of butter. Same with cheese. So what do I eat? The diagram below was the best visual aid I could find; however, I tend to put much less emphasis on meats, and more on avocados and eggs. Shrimp shouldn’t be on this chart either…that stuff is garbage. On most days, I’ll only have two meals, lunch and dinner, with one meal being meatless. My lunch typically consists of a cruciferous salad (kale, broccoli, cabbage, brussel sprouts), topped with hard boiled eggs, feta cheese, and avocado. For salad dressing, I make my own by simply combining a tablespoon of avocado oil and a tablespoon of rice wine vinegar. Luckily, Trader Joes sells the salad mix pre-made, so that saves a lot of prep time. For dinner, I’ll have a variety of options, from pork chops, to beef and broccoli, to cauliflower pizza, to taco bowls. I also grow my own broccoli sprouts in mason jars and top pretty much everything with those bitches. Do your research. There are a ton of recipe books and information online about keto now, so find out what foods you can and cannot eat, and experiment. It’s not that big a deal if you don’t stick 100% to keto…removing sugars from your diet is a huge improvement on its own. KETO PRO-TIP: If you want to save some money on your meats, buy chicken or beef that is lean. Then cook your proteins in good fat sources, like grass-fed butter. This is also a great option if you’re not sure about your meat quality too…when in doubt, get the leaner cuts and add your own fats during cooking. What have I observed after three months? 1) Bloating is gone. Do you wake up in the morning, look at yourself in the mirror, and look pretty good? Then by the end of the day you look fatter, and ‘bloated’ compared to the morning? I used to too! This is due to bloating. Since I started keto, I no longer retain a significant amount of water weight, and I look the same in the mirror all day long. 2) I’m a light-weight drinker. I can only drink about half of what I used to be able to before getting a buzz. Hangovers are much worse too. This is a common keto observation. This could be attributed to Observation #1, since your hydration levels are a big part of how alcohol affects you. 3) Maintaining weight is automatic. Prior to keto, I really had to manage my calories to stay around 170 lbs. Whenever I would get down to this weight, I’d be super hungry all the time, and would bounce back up to 180 over 2-3 months. I’d manage my weight by going through 3 month cycles of cuts and gains, so I didn’t constantly need to track calories. Since I’ve started keto, I’ve stayed stable at 170 without counting calories, and I’m rarely hungry shortly after meals. When I’m hungry, I eat. Never in my life have I been able to do this, and now nearing the ripe old age of 40, that’s quite a result. 4) Losing weight is far easier. Following from the prior observation, if I wanted to lose additional weight, I could do so quite easily by cutting out a snack here and there, or removing alcohol completely. Back when I used to go through cutting cycles, I’d spend all day looking forward to my next feeding. 5) Meals are more fulfilling. Try this experiment: For lunch, make five scrambled eggs, and a pack of (quality) bacon. Cook the eggs in a tablespoon of grass-fed butter. Eat all the eggs, and as many bacon strips as you want until you’re full. Now, see how many hours go by until you’re starving again. I bet you either don’t eat dinner, or have a light meal. You see, fats and proteins help you lose weight, because you can easily sustain a diet where you’re rarely hungry. 6) I still crave sweets. From time-to-time genetics and almost 40 years of bad-behaviors nag at me, and I want something sweet. I never eat sugary junk though, I learned to make keto cookies and peanut butter fat bombs. Other sweet-tooth satisfying options include: spoonful of peanut butter, small handful of dark chocolate, and keto friendly bars (i.e. Quest bars). Note, almost all protein bars aren’t good if you really want to stay in ketosis, so try to avoid them if you can, but they’re still decent options for quick snacks. 7) I’ve seen a slight drop-off at the gym. I’m on a strength-training focus right now (many sets, few reps), but I did notice a drop-off in progress once I switched to keto. That being said, the drop-off was only slight, and I’m still making good progress. There could also be other factors at play here too, such as hydration levels, age, progress naturally slows at higher weights, etc. I’ve heard other keto dieters observe this too, so something to keep in mind. I don’t do any pre-workout supplements, so that may be an option to mitigate the diet change too. 8) My digestive system is less predictable. Even three months later, I’m still going through various cycles of regularity and irregularity. I most certainly ‘go less’. Days where I feel uncomfortable get fewer and fewer as time goes on though, and as my gut microbiome adjusts to a new way of doing things. I’ve heard this can take months or even as long as a year to adjust, so I’m giving it time. I’ve also consciously added pro-biotic foods to my diet, such as sauerkraut and an occasional kombucha. 9) Less inflammation? I’m not sure. The lack of water retention would suggest my inflammation levels have dropped, but if I’m being honest, I can’t say for sure. I still have join aches and pains here and there, but the frequency and severity of these seems to have diminished. The changes aren’t super dramatic, so I can’t say for sure if this is due to the diet, or other factors. 10) Keto flu wasn’t severe. My previous diet was far from keto, but I had been eating healthy foods (salads, eggs, avocado) for awhile. I never ate fast-food and rarely sugary stuff like cookies or soda. Bread and rice were probably my big carb contributors. I think because of this, I missed most of the “keto flu” symptoms that many people report. Other than some constipation, I’m not sure I had any significant symptoms I would classify in this category. There you have it. Hopefully this will help you with your own health decisions. It can’t hurt to try it for a few months and see if it works for you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Most Played Board Games of 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/boardgames/2018/12/30/gamesof2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Most Played Board Games of 2018" /><published>2018-12-30T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/boardgames/2018/12/30/gamesof2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/boardgames/2018/12/30/gamesof2018.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s my list of my most played games this year. Party games (6+ players) tended to be big hits in my household, since game night usually coincided with having friends/family over to the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/coc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Codenames:&lt;/b&gt;  This game was by far the most played amongst my gaming group. This game can be played with both small and large groups, and the barrier to entry is basically non-existent. This is a game for all ages too. I think we played this game the most due to the simple fact that you could be playing a pretty great game with anyone within minutes. This game has no depth and little theme
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monikers:&lt;/b&gt;  This is the ultimate party game, as long as you have an even number of players. It's usually the most fun with eight or more players. Similar to Codenames, the barrier to entry is small, with the exception that some of the culture or history references may not be familiar to younger players (though the game addresses this with a description which it allows you to read out in the first round). I think the main reasons we played Codenames more than this game is you really need a decently sized group to play, and the 'even number of players' requirement is annoying (or at least the game works the best with even teams).
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;No Thanks:&lt;/b&gt;  Simple, easy to learn, quick, and good for large groups. This is a great warm-up game where you spend tokens to avoid getting cards (i.e. points). Fewest points wins. Not a ton of strategy, but what do you expect for an investment of two minutes to learn the game? This game is cheap, and even board game haters will enjoy this game. We often used this as a warm-up game, but never as the main game of the night.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Sale:&lt;/b&gt;  A little bit deeper than No Thanks, For Sale is an auction game where you buy properties, then sell those properties for points. This is a game for small groups, and has that low barrier of entry that make it a great option to introduce new people to board games. This game is also pretty cheap so you get a lot of plays for your dollar.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Star Wars Destiny:&lt;/b&gt;  This blows away all other two-player games for the best dueling game of 2018. I'm very skeptical of any Star Wars licensed game, and this game really feels like 'Star Wars'. It's pretty easy to learn, the turns are quick, and you feel like you have tons of strategy and press-your-luck options on every turn. Rather than falling into the endless money pit of buying packs, I created two interesting theme decks (Stormtroopers vs Luke and Yoda), filled them with singles bought on eBay, and just play with those cards. The combination of cards and dice rolling is a blast and was designed exceptionally well.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bang The Dice Game:&lt;/b&gt;  This is an extremely fun game in the early rounds, but starts to taper off once you start eliminating players. Most of my gamers friends found the character roles confusing, and frankly I find them confusing too. If I'm the Outlaw, am I supposed to kill the Sheriff or the Renegade? Wait let me look it up, hang on let me re-read it, etc. Other games like Coup and The Resistance seem to pull off role based games without issues. Works pretty well for larger groups, but I'd rather play King of Tokyo for a small group.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;King of Tokyo:&lt;/b&gt;  I'm not sure why I love this game so much. The concept of being a giant monster fighting other monsters is just so hilarious to me. The base game is probably a bit to simple, so I immediately added the Power Up expansion, and the Chuthulu monster expansion, which both add additional powers depending on rolls. This is very similar to Bang The Dice Game, but without the role confusion.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arkham Horror The Card Game:&lt;/b&gt;  The theme and story of this game override the faults I have with it, but this game probably won't be on my 2019 list. I played this game a bunch in 2018, but I'm done with it. It's simply too much maintenance inside and outside of the game. If this were the only game I owned, I would not be disappointed, but there are just too many other games on my shelf that are easier to setup/teach, have less monotonous game mechanics, don't require me to buy expansions to keep the game interesting, and scratch the same 'card game' itch. It's worth buying the starter set to play through that campaign though, and just consider this a stand-alone game. For the price ($25 right now on Amazon), it's hard to beat.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ethnos:&lt;/b&gt;  This is a hybrid of Ticket to Ride and a simplified version of Risk. Really quick turns, easy to learn, interesting strategies to earn points, and not a terrible theme. The theme doesn't really do much for the game though, this is a borderline abstract game. Also, it's really hard to connect if your strategy is working, or if you're just drawing lucky cards. This game is always fun to play, but I'm still not sure if I'm good at it or not.

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;--2018 Biggest Surprises--&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dread:&lt;/b&gt;  Dread is a D&amp;amp;D style horror game where the success of actions taken by your character is determined by pulling blocks on a Jenga tower. We played this during Halloween, and my group absolutely loved the format. The success of this game is very depended upon your DM though. I used one of the story scenarios from Dread book, but added a few dice rolling elements, sound effects, and props. Afterwards, my friends wanted to dress up the next time we played and make a whole event out of it. My only complaint is the limited number of scenarios, and some of them aren't that interesting to me.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;--2018 Disappointments--&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mysterium:&lt;/b&gt;  The gaming community has raved about this game, but I just didn't like it. Luckily I got a good deal for it on eBay. I feel like a collaborative game needs to have strong stakes or consequences if the team doesn't make it to the end. Plus it should have a big pay off if you are successful. Forbidden Desert does a great job of this...build a ship to escape, or watch your friends slowly die in the desert. Mysterium doesn't have these stakes...oh well, we didn't figure out the killer, whatever. Or, only half the group figured out the killer and somehow we all won. Or, what's the point of the entire first round if we don't figure out the killer until the second round. I don't know...the theme was there and it was strong, but it just didn't make sense to me. I'd rather play the picture version of Codenames.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;San Juan:&lt;/b&gt;  This is another game that's great at the start, but becomes monotonous towards the end of the game. As your tableau of cards grows, you have so many actions and abilities to remember, we found ourselves constantly forgetting to do certain actions. This was a recent purchase though, and I've only played it once, so I'd like to play a few more times before saying for sure that I don't like this game.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arkham Horror The Card Game:&lt;/b&gt;  Wait, this is on the most played list too? Although I played this game a bunch, it did have its disappointments. A very logical flow to a game is: you take a turn, I take a turn, repeat. However, this game includes a maintenance step at every round where you need to draw cards for the monsters. I hate this mechanic...can't this be incorporated into the player's turn? Munckin does a great job of making exploration of the deck feel like part of the game, rather than 'maintenance' you have to perform once you're done having fun on your turn. Game designers, stop giving me work do to. I did feel like you had too much to remember too...we would constantly be forgetting turn steps, or 'oh yeah I forgot I had this bonus/ability', etc, even in the early scenarios. These complaints aside, if that stuff doesn't bother you, Arkham Horror TCG really is a great game with an excellent theme and story. You truly feel like you're taking on cultists to save the city of Arkham.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lords of Vegas:&lt;/b&gt; The best way to describe this game is &quot;better Monopoly&quot;. The theme and strategies of the game are interesting; however, the turn maintenance feels like work. Between every turn, you need to play accountant, auditing the board and passing out points. It gets old quick and slows the game down. Maintenance steps in board games are my least favorite design mechanics.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;--Games I'm Most Looking Forward To--&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chronicles of Crime:&lt;/b&gt;  To be honest, I did play the first three scenarios of this game over Christmas break, and this game is excellent. It's easy to learn, has a deep theme, interesting story and characters, and is expandable through the app. Scanning everything does get a little tedious, but it's way better than looking up tables like you would do with similar games like Tales of Arabian Nights. Also, it would have been great if the app designer added voice actors, rather than players reading from the app. If voice actors were added, this would probably displace Pandemic Legacy for my greatest game of all time (so far).
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Keyforge:&lt;/b&gt;  I've played a few hands of Keyforge too, and this game is surprisingly fun. Game turns are quick, but you still feel like you can do a lot on your turn. Actions during your turn are in a logical order, and do a great job of opening opportunities (a lot of games feel handcuffed by turn orders, action amounts, etc). I rarely had the 'oh yeah I forgot I had this ability' problem that I had constantly with Arkham Horror, and other duel games (Star Wars Destiny had this problem too, to a smaller degree). I wish the theme wasn't so abstract, but this isn't a deal breaker for me. I just figured the game designer was sick of the elves/dwarves/wizards/orcs formula in every game, and went more for a SmashUp theme. Not my favorite theme idea, but I'll roll with it.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Viticulture:&lt;/b&gt;  I don't own this game get, but I have a gift card for the local game store burning a hole in my pocket. I've watched a ton of review videos about this game, and frankly the theme or gameplay doesn't seem all that compelling. However, I can't ignore the endless amount of positive buzz about this game, and how high it seems to appear on basically every game reviewer's list of 2018 games.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Here’s my list of my most played games this year. Party games (6+ players) tended to be big hits in my household, since game night usually coincided with having friends/family over to the house.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windkeep - Part 4: The Mistake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/23/windkeep004.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windkeep - Part 4: The Mistake" /><published>2018-12-23T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-23T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/23/windkeep004</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/23/windkeep004.html">&lt;p&gt;It was approaching late afternoon, and the sun began to sink towards the mountains in the western sky. The invading force of the Scarlett horde was now clearly visible to the south, halting their approach atop a large, mostly treeless hill. The hill would provide them good visibility of both Windkeep and the battlefield, but also provide elevated cover from possible counter attacks. Knowing the numbers of the Windkeep defenders, a counter-attack at this point would be highly unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first wave of attack was nothing more than an attempt to expose our tactics and numbers. Small, uncoordinated groups of fighters ran towards the wall, then back towards the Horde encampment, some of which firing arrows into the city in an attempt to antagonize, and possibly demoralize, the defenders. I advised Vargas that this might happen, so he commanded his one hundred or so men to stand their ground and not react to the attackers. They were all well trained solders, Vargas and Krueger were both clearly effective leaders, and we continued to hide behind the safety of the city wall until the Horde commanders were satisfied we weren’t going to take the bait. We were hoping the city would appear abandoned, from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fighters of the first wave were pulled back into formation with the rest of the force, and the front lines of infantry began to march towards Windkeep. Peering between the wooden slats in the wall, I counted two-thousand men, by best estimation. Two catapults also began to follow the incoming wave, spread out evenly behind the protection of the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The catapults will be a problem,” I thought to myself as I prepared two spells, one in each hand, still crouched behind the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The troops marched forward, as the catapults came to a stop, apparently reaching an adequate spot within their range to bombard the city. One of the middle catapults fired its payload, and a dark object, presumably a stone, sailed through the air towards Windkeep. As the projectile reached the edge of the city, I stood up with my outstretched arms pointing at the object. Now that it was close enough to clearly identify the object as a boulder, I released the spell energy in my right hand. A localized, yet extremely powerful gust of wind exploded from my hand, and pushed the boulder off-course. It sailed harmlessly short of its original target, smacked into the hard earth near the base of the wall, and shattered into several large pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did I mention I’m glad you’re here?” Vargas said, with a smile. “That thing probably would have punched right through the wall.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have a long way to go,” I replied, grimly. I had expected the Scarlett Horde to be not much more than a rag-tag group of mindless warriors whose primary advantage was sheer numbers, but their tactics were starting to reveal a level of coordination I had not anticipated. Pushing the doubt into the back of my mind, I readied another wind spell in my right hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another catapult prepared to fire, but this time the projectile was set ablaze. It launched through the air with roughly the same trajectory as the previous attempt. As the fireball approached the wall, I once again extended my arms toward the object, this time releasing the energy in my left hand. A large sphere of water materialized in the path of the fireball, extinguishing its flames as the projectile exploded through the wall of water. The object had not been significantly slowed by the water, and it impacted the city wall, harmlessly sticking to the wooden beams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Must have been a ball of tar,” said Vargas. “They must not be keen on preserving too much of the city if they’re willing to burn everything down. Anything you can do about those catapults?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not from this distance,” I replied. “But let’s keep our eyes peeled for opportunities. Fortunately there are only two of them and they take a few minutes to reload.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Horde infantry continued to press forward, and a nod from Vargas indicated he thought they were just about to enter in the range of his archers. I returned the nod and he stood with his arm raised in the air, indicating to his solders to prepare to fire. Each solder nocked an arrow onto their bows, and set their feet in preparation. Vargas watched the incoming troops a moment longer, judging the distance, then quickly lowered his arm. A cloud of arrows erupted from the wall towards the marching infantry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within moments, the onslaught of arrows had nearly reached their targets, and the Horde troopers raised their small wooden shields in defense. Just as the arrows were about to hit their targets, a bolt of lightning shot from the rear of the Horde ranks, and connected with a single arrow within the center of the sea of arrows. The impact of lightening and arrow transitioned into a flash of white light, and dozens of additional lightening bolts extended out, originating from the point of impact. These bolts branched out into a web of lightening, each impacting their own arrow, to branch out again to additional arrows. The entire process completed in less than a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Horde troopers, lowering their shields and seeming somewhat confused by what had just transpired, marched forward once again. Not a single arrow had reached its destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned towards Vargas, who had lost most of the color in his face. “Shit,” I said, “they have their own wizard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly cast a magic detection spell to validate what I already knew. The world darkened before me, the spell working to highlight any people or objects with magical properties; however, the gold glow of a magical source didn’t appear anywhere within the Horde ranks. I waived off the detection spell and recharged my catapult defense spells, wind in one hand and water in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The other mage is smart,” I thought to myself, realizing my first major mistake of the battle. “He must have activated an anti-detection protection spell. I should have done the same.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To be continued…&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">It was approaching late afternoon, and the sun began to sink towards the mountains in the western sky. The invading force of the Scarlett horde was now clearly visible to the south, halting their approach atop a large, mostly treeless hill. The hill would provide them good visibility of both Windkeep and the battlefield, but also provide elevated cover from possible counter attacks. Knowing the numbers of the Windkeep defenders, a counter-attack at this point would be highly unlikely. The first wave of attack was nothing more than an attempt to expose our tactics and numbers. Small, uncoordinated groups of fighters ran towards the wall, then back towards the Horde encampment, some of which firing arrows into the city in an attempt to antagonize, and possibly demoralize, the defenders. I advised Vargas that this might happen, so he commanded his one hundred or so men to stand their ground and not react to the attackers. They were all well trained solders, Vargas and Krueger were both clearly effective leaders, and we continued to hide behind the safety of the city wall until the Horde commanders were satisfied we weren’t going to take the bait. We were hoping the city would appear abandoned, from their perspective. The fighters of the first wave were pulled back into formation with the rest of the force, and the front lines of infantry began to march towards Windkeep. Peering between the wooden slats in the wall, I counted two-thousand men, by best estimation. Two catapults also began to follow the incoming wave, spread out evenly behind the protection of the lines. “The catapults will be a problem,” I thought to myself as I prepared two spells, one in each hand, still crouched behind the wall. The troops marched forward, as the catapults came to a stop, apparently reaching an adequate spot within their range to bombard the city. One of the middle catapults fired its payload, and a dark object, presumably a stone, sailed through the air towards Windkeep. As the projectile reached the edge of the city, I stood up with my outstretched arms pointing at the object. Now that it was close enough to clearly identify the object as a boulder, I released the spell energy in my right hand. A localized, yet extremely powerful gust of wind exploded from my hand, and pushed the boulder off-course. It sailed harmlessly short of its original target, smacked into the hard earth near the base of the wall, and shattered into several large pieces. “Did I mention I’m glad you’re here?” Vargas said, with a smile. “That thing probably would have punched right through the wall.” “We have a long way to go,” I replied, grimly. I had expected the Scarlett Horde to be not much more than a rag-tag group of mindless warriors whose primary advantage was sheer numbers, but their tactics were starting to reveal a level of coordination I had not anticipated. Pushing the doubt into the back of my mind, I readied another wind spell in my right hand. Another catapult prepared to fire, but this time the projectile was set ablaze. It launched through the air with roughly the same trajectory as the previous attempt. As the fireball approached the wall, I once again extended my arms toward the object, this time releasing the energy in my left hand. A large sphere of water materialized in the path of the fireball, extinguishing its flames as the projectile exploded through the wall of water. The object had not been significantly slowed by the water, and it impacted the city wall, harmlessly sticking to the wooden beams. “Must have been a ball of tar,” said Vargas. “They must not be keen on preserving too much of the city if they’re willing to burn everything down. Anything you can do about those catapults?” “Not from this distance,” I replied. “But let’s keep our eyes peeled for opportunities. Fortunately there are only two of them and they take a few minutes to reload.” The Horde infantry continued to press forward, and a nod from Vargas indicated he thought they were just about to enter in the range of his archers. I returned the nod and he stood with his arm raised in the air, indicating to his solders to prepare to fire. Each solder nocked an arrow onto their bows, and set their feet in preparation. Vargas watched the incoming troops a moment longer, judging the distance, then quickly lowered his arm. A cloud of arrows erupted from the wall towards the marching infantry. Within moments, the onslaught of arrows had nearly reached their targets, and the Horde troopers raised their small wooden shields in defense. Just as the arrows were about to hit their targets, a bolt of lightning shot from the rear of the Horde ranks, and connected with a single arrow within the center of the sea of arrows. The impact of lightening and arrow transitioned into a flash of white light, and dozens of additional lightening bolts extended out, originating from the point of impact. These bolts branched out into a web of lightening, each impacting their own arrow, to branch out again to additional arrows. The entire process completed in less than a few seconds. The Horde troopers, lowering their shields and seeming somewhat confused by what had just transpired, marched forward once again. Not a single arrow had reached its destination. I turned towards Vargas, who had lost most of the color in his face. “Shit,” I said, “they have their own wizard.” I quickly cast a magic detection spell to validate what I already knew. The world darkened before me, the spell working to highlight any people or objects with magical properties; however, the gold glow of a magical source didn’t appear anywhere within the Horde ranks. I waived off the detection spell and recharged my catapult defense spells, wind in one hand and water in the other. “The other mage is smart,” I thought to myself, realizing my first major mistake of the battle. “He must have activated an anti-detection protection spell. I should have done the same.” To be continued…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windkeep - Part 3: Attrition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/21/windkeep003.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windkeep - Part 3: Attrition" /><published>2018-12-21T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/21/windkeep003</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/21/windkeep003.html">&lt;p&gt;“The scouting party has returned!” the young guard shouted as he burst into my room, startling me from the best night sleep I’ve had in weeks. “Krueger just finished their debriefing…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat up in bed and rubbed my eyes. “Ok, I’ll be there,” I said, groggily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guard excitedly slammed the door shut and bounded off down the hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t the most extravagant inn-room I’ve ever stayed in, but the beds of the Black Oak Inn were far better than the dirt, rock, and twigs I was used to back on the road. The room was small, containing only the bed, a desk with chair, and a cabinet. A window next to the bed provided me an excellent view of the town square, and gave a much more open feeling to an otherwise claustrophobic room. Based on the position of the sun in the sky, I calculated it was mid-day. I’m not a late sleeper by habit, but the added rest was certainly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reluctantly pulled myself out of bed, got dressed, and opened the cabinet to retrieve my belongings. My pack was just as heavy as I remembered it, though still lighter than normal due to diminishing provisions. I slung the pack over my shoulder, opened the room door, and proceeded down the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air of excitement was thick as I walked down the stairway into the inn’s tavern. Half a dozen soldiers stood at the bar, all with mugs of ale in their hands, and exuberantly chatted amongst each other. Kreuger sat at a nearby table studying a map of the area and discussing strategy with one of his officers. He looked up and smiled when he noticed my approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry to wake you so early,” Krueger said. He nodded towards the soldiers at the bar, “Our missing scouting party has returned…it turns out they weren’t lost or captured.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good news,” I said. “What happened to them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officer standing next to Krueger chimed in, “We were trenched up by the Horde.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krueger continued, “Conrad, this is Lieutenant Vargas. He led the scouting party.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We found their camp in the glade, just where we thought it would be,” Vargas said while pointing a spot on the map, just south of Windkeep. “We were lucky to get out alive. We weren’t expecting to encounter such a large force, so we spent more time hiding in bushes than marching back to Windkeep. I couldn’t risk getting captured or killed. Our intelligence was vital.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What did you discover?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Their numbers are in the thousands. Armor, weaponry, siege weapons, you name it, they have it,” Vargas said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought they were just group of thieves?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s all we’ve seen up until this point,” Krueger explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vargas let out a sigh, “We think the thieves were really scouts sent to gather supplies and test our defenses. We don’t really have a lot of experience dealing with armies in this region.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krueger nodded, “Based off Vargas’ information, we believe they are massing a force to launch an assault on Windkeep.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incredulous look on my face was telling. “For what purpose?” I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For financial gain, to establish a foothold in the region, just to terrorize…who knows?” Vargas said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krueger shook his head. “And I’ve got one hundred fifty city guards and one wizard standing between the people of Windkeep and their utter destruction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have to evacuate the city,” I said bluntly. Military tactics and how mages play a part in them was a major field of study for graduating wizards. Along with magic, art, philosophy, chemistry, and engineering, I was well educated in areas of war, so even I knew the town defenses would never hold out. The city walls and an entrenched position would give the soldiers of Windkeep a tactical advantage, but the sheer number of attackers would overwhelm them. A defeat by attrition is still a defeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where would we evacuate to?” Vargas said. “And if we did evacuate, that would just leave us for slaughter along the road. At least here, in Windkeep, we have the walls to protect us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I believe the walls will be insufficient,” I said to Krueger. “I say with humility that I am a powerful wizard. I graduated at the top of my class from the Wizard’s Institute, and I have talents and magical abilities most other mages will never elevate to. Even I, however, have my limitations. I can assist your forces, but I cannot win this battle for them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lively atmosphere of the tavern had turned to melancholy, and I realized the scouting party at the bar was listening in on our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a long look at the men at the bar, and then turned back to Krueger, “I’ll need a spot along the wall, where I have a good view of the battlefield.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;……….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it weren’t for the threat of battle brooding on the horizon, anyone would agree that it was an absolutely beautiful afternoon in Windkeep. The air was warm, with a cool breeze from the north, and the excellent visibility allowed for early detection of the enemy forces approaching over a ridge to the south. Although impossible to see with the naked eye, a magnification spell allowed me to easily see the Horde banners and catapults the moment they popped into view. The main force was still at least an hour away, so Krueger and Vargas were busily preparing for the town’s defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, on the other hand, stood in the center of the southern wall parapet, mentally preparing myself for the enormous release of magical energy I would inevitably drain from my body. A keen mind and the ability to maintain concentration was vital in spell-casting. A good mage should be able to focus even when completely exhausted. I knew this day would be a testament to my stamina, since casting spells was fundamentally a release of body energy, focused into different patterns. I was more curious than anxious to see how I would fare in such a large scale assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you have everything you need?” Vargas said, as he ran up to stand next to me along the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both looked off into the horizon for a moment, and I replied, “Yes, this should be an adequate view for the duration of the battle. I will be deep in concentration for the majority of the battle, so I’d appreciate it if someone could watch my back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Already taken care of, Conrad,” Vargas said, “Krueger has assigned me as your personal bodyguard. He’ll be stationed at the southeast corner of the wall, directing our forces and watching for possible flanking maneuvers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I assume they’ll attack us in waves to make themselves harder targets for our bowmen and to give the front lines a chance to rest,” I surmised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We assumed that as well,” Vargas said. “We’ll position most of our men along the wall with bow and arrow, and the remainder on standby to replenish fallen men and fill the gaps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If they breach the wall the battle is over,” I observed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vargas rubbed the back of his head. “Agreed,” he said, as we both turned to look at the threat slowly growing in the distance .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To be continued…&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">“The scouting party has returned!” the young guard shouted as he burst into my room, startling me from the best night sleep I’ve had in weeks. “Krueger just finished their debriefing…” I sat up in bed and rubbed my eyes. “Ok, I’ll be there,” I said, groggily. The guard excitedly slammed the door shut and bounded off down the hall. It wasn’t the most extravagant inn-room I’ve ever stayed in, but the beds of the Black Oak Inn were far better than the dirt, rock, and twigs I was used to back on the road. The room was small, containing only the bed, a desk with chair, and a cabinet. A window next to the bed provided me an excellent view of the town square, and gave a much more open feeling to an otherwise claustrophobic room. Based on the position of the sun in the sky, I calculated it was mid-day. I’m not a late sleeper by habit, but the added rest was certainly welcome. I reluctantly pulled myself out of bed, got dressed, and opened the cabinet to retrieve my belongings. My pack was just as heavy as I remembered it, though still lighter than normal due to diminishing provisions. I slung the pack over my shoulder, opened the room door, and proceeded down the hallway. The air of excitement was thick as I walked down the stairway into the inn’s tavern. Half a dozen soldiers stood at the bar, all with mugs of ale in their hands, and exuberantly chatted amongst each other. Kreuger sat at a nearby table studying a map of the area and discussing strategy with one of his officers. He looked up and smiled when he noticed my approach. “Sorry to wake you so early,” Krueger said. He nodded towards the soldiers at the bar, “Our missing scouting party has returned…it turns out they weren’t lost or captured.” “Good news,” I said. “What happened to them?” The officer standing next to Krueger chimed in, “We were trenched up by the Horde.” Krueger continued, “Conrad, this is Lieutenant Vargas. He led the scouting party.” “We found their camp in the glade, just where we thought it would be,” Vargas said while pointing a spot on the map, just south of Windkeep. “We were lucky to get out alive. We weren’t expecting to encounter such a large force, so we spent more time hiding in bushes than marching back to Windkeep. I couldn’t risk getting captured or killed. Our intelligence was vital.” “What did you discover?” I asked. “Their numbers are in the thousands. Armor, weaponry, siege weapons, you name it, they have it,” Vargas said. “I thought they were just group of thieves?” I asked. “That’s all we’ve seen up until this point,” Krueger explained. Vargas let out a sigh, “We think the thieves were really scouts sent to gather supplies and test our defenses. We don’t really have a lot of experience dealing with armies in this region.” Krueger nodded, “Based off Vargas’ information, we believe they are massing a force to launch an assault on Windkeep.” The incredulous look on my face was telling. “For what purpose?” I asked. “For financial gain, to establish a foothold in the region, just to terrorize…who knows?” Vargas said. Krueger shook his head. “And I’ve got one hundred fifty city guards and one wizard standing between the people of Windkeep and their utter destruction.” “You have to evacuate the city,” I said bluntly. Military tactics and how mages play a part in them was a major field of study for graduating wizards. Along with magic, art, philosophy, chemistry, and engineering, I was well educated in areas of war, so even I knew the town defenses would never hold out. The city walls and an entrenched position would give the soldiers of Windkeep a tactical advantage, but the sheer number of attackers would overwhelm them. A defeat by attrition is still a defeat. “Where would we evacuate to?” Vargas said. “And if we did evacuate, that would just leave us for slaughter along the road. At least here, in Windkeep, we have the walls to protect us.” “I believe the walls will be insufficient,” I said to Krueger. “I say with humility that I am a powerful wizard. I graduated at the top of my class from the Wizard’s Institute, and I have talents and magical abilities most other mages will never elevate to. Even I, however, have my limitations. I can assist your forces, but I cannot win this battle for them.” The lively atmosphere of the tavern had turned to melancholy, and I realized the scouting party at the bar was listening in on our conversation. I took a long look at the men at the bar, and then turned back to Krueger, “I’ll need a spot along the wall, where I have a good view of the battlefield.” ………. If it weren’t for the threat of battle brooding on the horizon, anyone would agree that it was an absolutely beautiful afternoon in Windkeep. The air was warm, with a cool breeze from the north, and the excellent visibility allowed for early detection of the enemy forces approaching over a ridge to the south. Although impossible to see with the naked eye, a magnification spell allowed me to easily see the Horde banners and catapults the moment they popped into view. The main force was still at least an hour away, so Krueger and Vargas were busily preparing for the town’s defense. I, on the other hand, stood in the center of the southern wall parapet, mentally preparing myself for the enormous release of magical energy I would inevitably drain from my body. A keen mind and the ability to maintain concentration was vital in spell-casting. A good mage should be able to focus even when completely exhausted. I knew this day would be a testament to my stamina, since casting spells was fundamentally a release of body energy, focused into different patterns. I was more curious than anxious to see how I would fare in such a large scale assault. “Do you have everything you need?” Vargas said, as he ran up to stand next to me along the wall. We both looked off into the horizon for a moment, and I replied, “Yes, this should be an adequate view for the duration of the battle. I will be deep in concentration for the majority of the battle, so I’d appreciate it if someone could watch my back.” “Already taken care of, Conrad,” Vargas said, “Krueger has assigned me as your personal bodyguard. He’ll be stationed at the southeast corner of the wall, directing our forces and watching for possible flanking maneuvers. “I assume they’ll attack us in waves to make themselves harder targets for our bowmen and to give the front lines a chance to rest,” I surmised. “We assumed that as well,” Vargas said. “We’ll position most of our men along the wall with bow and arrow, and the remainder on standby to replenish fallen men and fill the gaps.” “If they breach the wall the battle is over,” I observed. Vargas rubbed the back of his head. “Agreed,” he said, as we both turned to look at the threat slowly growing in the distance . To be continued…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Bio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/21/aboutbrian.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Bio" /><published>2018-12-21T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/21/aboutbrian</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/21/aboutbrian.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! I’m Brian. As an IT guy and relatively well-versed in IT security, I’m very hesitant to post personal identifying information online. However, the below information is relatively safe, so here’s a very brief bio:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Info Last Updated: December 21, 2018&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Born:&lt;/b&gt; 1979  &lt;i&gt;(not a millennial)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Residence:&lt;/b&gt; Southern California (currently City of Brea)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Education:&lt;/b&gt; California State University, Fullerton (BS Computer Science, MS IT Management)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Employment:&lt;/b&gt; IT Manager, Web Developer, Sys Admin, Enterprise Architect, Terrible Writer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Hobbies:&lt;/b&gt; Dad (15+ yrs), Weight-lifting (2+ yrs), Sailing (&amp;lt;1 yr), Keto Cooking (&amp;lt;1 yr), Bowling, Softball&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Hello! I’m Brian. As an IT guy and relatively well-versed in IT security, I’m very hesitant to post personal identifying information online. However, the below information is relatively safe, so here’s a very brief bio: Info Last Updated: December 21, 2018 Born: 1979 (not a millennial) Residence: Southern California (currently City of Brea) Education: California State University, Fullerton (BS Computer Science, MS IT Management) Employment: IT Manager, Web Developer, Sys Admin, Enterprise Architect, Terrible Writer Other Hobbies: Dad (15+ yrs), Weight-lifting (2+ yrs), Sailing (&amp;lt;1 yr), Keto Cooking (&amp;lt;1 yr), Bowling, Softball</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windkeep - Part 2: The Scarlet Horde</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/19/windkeep002.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windkeep - Part 2: The Scarlet Horde" /><published>2018-12-19T08:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-19T08:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/19/windkeep002</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/19/windkeep002.html">&lt;p&gt;The thick foliage of Oakdale began to dissipate as the afternoon slowly dimmed to evening. Despite an unlucky encounter with a couple of thieves, it took me less than a day to cover the thirty miles from the bottom of Mount Baldy to the town of Windkeep, evidence of which I could now see off in the distance. Smoke from several chimneys rose between the trees and the sounds of a bustling thoroughfare began to resonate in my ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued over the crest of the final hill of my journey, and the elevation gave me a spectacular view of the entire city. Dozens of citizens meandered about the streets, which weaved in and out of the houses and buildings. I could tell the marketplace and the town proper was on the side of the city I was approaching, since most of the larger buildings were concentrated in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My bag was becoming heavy from a week of continuous travel and the sight of a town guaranteed an evening of creature comforts I’ve long missed. The life of a wandering mage wasn’t a luxurious one, but a hot bath and a soft bed was certainly an effective method of working out the aches and pains of a long journey. It would probably take a day or two before I could arrange for my own cabin, so I was looking forward to treating myself at the local inn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally approached the entrance to the town, where several guards were stationed. They were rough looking and dirty, and both anxiously jumped to attention when they noticed my approach. The older, scruffier-looking guard moved towards me, while the other, younger and appearing much more nervous, discretely lifted his spear. The older guard held his position a short distance in front of me and instinctively moved his hand to the hilt of his sword, still sheathed at his belt. So as not to startle them, I stopped walking and stood silent, waiting for the guards to make the first move. The level of apprehension was unexpected, so I figured it was best to find out more about what was going on before volunteering any information about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older guard was first to break the silence, “Who are you and what is your business in Windkeep?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am merely a traveler seeking a room and a meal,” I said as my attention shifted to the younger guard, who was now flanking my position to the right. “And, if at all possible, I’d like to arrange a meeting with your magistrate. I had an encounter on the road, not far from here, with a few thieves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The road outside of Windkeep is of little concern to the magistrate,” the older guard declared, “since he’s dead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could see three more guards running up to our position from the village, and I, once again, found myself preparing a defensive spell. This trip had not gone as smoothly as I had hoped. “That is unfortunate to hear,” I sympathized. “What exactly has happened here? My understanding was Windkeep was a peaceful, welcoming village.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guard briefly looked over his shoulder to confirm the arrival of additional guards and then relaxed his hand from his sword, “We were a peaceful village, traveler. Until a group calling themselves the Scarlet Horde moved into the glade, just south of here. The village magistrate was murdered in his sleep two weeks ago by one of their assassins, and they’ve been hitting merchant caravans ever since. It’s likely your thieves were part of that group. I take it your coin purse is much lighter now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Actually the thieves came to find that I was more than capable of defending myself,” I said as I threw back my traveling cloak to reveal my dark-blue wizard robes. “My name is Conrad and I’ve traveled from the Magical Arts Institute in Belgarath to take up residence here in Windkeep. I believe I can help you with this thief problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining guards relaxed their armaments and I allowed the spell energy stored in my hand to dissipate back into my body. The older guard approached me with a smile on his face, and reached out, shaking my hand, “Your help will be most appreciated, mage. Windkeep has been under martial rule since the death of the magistrate. I’ll take you to see Kreuger, the captain of the City Guard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We entered through the city gates as those passing by stopped to take notice of the new arrival. It was clear from their faces that the last few weeks had been tiresome, and I was hoping my arrival wouldn’t muster any false hope. I was only a single mage, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was led through the city square. Now, with a closer view of the buildings, the scars of battle on the town were visible. Broken windows were reinforced with wooden planks, several carts were turned on their sides and strategically placed as barricades, and patrolling guardsmen eyed me suspiciously as we passed by. Citizens were busily bringing in supplies, repairing downed structures, and putting out small fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s been a rough couple of weeks,” my guide explained as we entered the door of a small building. Above the door hung a carved wooden sign, picturing a dark, lifeless tree surrounded by gold lettering. The sign read: The Black Oak Inn. “The people are worried the town defenses are going to be overrun by the Scarlet Horde. There is talk about abandoning the village. Some have left already.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entering the inn, I could tell the first floor normally served as the local pub, but today it was headquarters to the city defense force. A muscular man with dark hair, thick war armor, and an expensive-looking sword at his belt, stood at the bar. He spoke with several young guards. Based on his tone of authority, my intuition told me this was Krueger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long has it been since the scouting party left?” Krueger asked his officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Two days ago,” the young guard nervously replied. “It was only an eight hour mission at most. They should have reported back yesterday. Shall I organize a search party, Captain?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” Krueger paused, noticing my entrance. “They are lost or the Horde found them. Either way, I can’t spare the men. Return to your post and shore up the southern defenses. Dismissed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes sir,” the guard said grimly as he led the other officers out of the inn. This left Krueger, myself, and my guard escort alone in the inn’s tavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What have we here, Bigsley?” Krueger asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is Conrad,” the guard explained. “He entered from the eastern gate. Claims to be from Belgarath, sir…from the wizard’s academy?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re a mage? Why have you come to Oak Dale?” Krueger investigated. I could tell from his tone that his pessimism was winning the battle against his optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To be honest,” I replied, “I had no knowledge of your current situation. Ironically, I came to Windkeep for the solitude, and the peace and quiet. Ideal conditions for the study of magic.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can assure you,” Krueger interrupted, “there is no peace here. The Horde attacks randomly, sometimes only to set fires to our village walls and buildings. Our guards have been able to force them back into the woods so far, but our numbers have dwindled over time, and it seems like the Horde’s have been increasing. And I’m sure you’ve heard about the death of our magistrate…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” I said. “Have you requested aid from other provinces?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are so remote, here,” he explained. “Scouting parties never return and convoys are attacked and forced to retreat back into the city. I’m afraid if this goes on much longer, I’ll have to order the evacuation of Windkeep.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a moment to consider my options. I could head back the way I came and leave these people to their own problems, or I could help them fight the Scarlet Horde. When I left Belgarath, I was determined to make Windkeep my home, and if I’ve learned anything about myself over the years, it’s that I don’t get ideas out of my head easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d like to assist in the fight,” I said abruptly, before I could talk myself out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The addition of a magic wielder to our forces will be a great benefit, Conrad. Welcome to the Windkeep City Guard,” Krueger said with a smile, as he vigorously grabbed my hand and shook it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These people were more desperate than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To be continued…&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">The thick foliage of Oakdale began to dissipate as the afternoon slowly dimmed to evening. Despite an unlucky encounter with a couple of thieves, it took me less than a day to cover the thirty miles from the bottom of Mount Baldy to the town of Windkeep, evidence of which I could now see off in the distance. Smoke from several chimneys rose between the trees and the sounds of a bustling thoroughfare began to resonate in my ears. I continued over the crest of the final hill of my journey, and the elevation gave me a spectacular view of the entire city. Dozens of citizens meandered about the streets, which weaved in and out of the houses and buildings. I could tell the marketplace and the town proper was on the side of the city I was approaching, since most of the larger buildings were concentrated in that area. My bag was becoming heavy from a week of continuous travel and the sight of a town guaranteed an evening of creature comforts I’ve long missed. The life of a wandering mage wasn’t a luxurious one, but a hot bath and a soft bed was certainly an effective method of working out the aches and pains of a long journey. It would probably take a day or two before I could arrange for my own cabin, so I was looking forward to treating myself at the local inn. I finally approached the entrance to the town, where several guards were stationed. They were rough looking and dirty, and both anxiously jumped to attention when they noticed my approach. The older, scruffier-looking guard moved towards me, while the other, younger and appearing much more nervous, discretely lifted his spear. The older guard held his position a short distance in front of me and instinctively moved his hand to the hilt of his sword, still sheathed at his belt. So as not to startle them, I stopped walking and stood silent, waiting for the guards to make the first move. The level of apprehension was unexpected, so I figured it was best to find out more about what was going on before volunteering any information about myself. The older guard was first to break the silence, “Who are you and what is your business in Windkeep?” “I am merely a traveler seeking a room and a meal,” I said as my attention shifted to the younger guard, who was now flanking my position to the right. “And, if at all possible, I’d like to arrange a meeting with your magistrate. I had an encounter on the road, not far from here, with a few thieves.” “The road outside of Windkeep is of little concern to the magistrate,” the older guard declared, “since he’s dead.” I could see three more guards running up to our position from the village, and I, once again, found myself preparing a defensive spell. This trip had not gone as smoothly as I had hoped. “That is unfortunate to hear,” I sympathized. “What exactly has happened here? My understanding was Windkeep was a peaceful, welcoming village.” The guard briefly looked over his shoulder to confirm the arrival of additional guards and then relaxed his hand from his sword, “We were a peaceful village, traveler. Until a group calling themselves the Scarlet Horde moved into the glade, just south of here. The village magistrate was murdered in his sleep two weeks ago by one of their assassins, and they’ve been hitting merchant caravans ever since. It’s likely your thieves were part of that group. I take it your coin purse is much lighter now?” “Actually the thieves came to find that I was more than capable of defending myself,” I said as I threw back my traveling cloak to reveal my dark-blue wizard robes. “My name is Conrad and I’ve traveled from the Magical Arts Institute in Belgarath to take up residence here in Windkeep. I believe I can help you with this thief problem.” The remaining guards relaxed their armaments and I allowed the spell energy stored in my hand to dissipate back into my body. The older guard approached me with a smile on his face, and reached out, shaking my hand, “Your help will be most appreciated, mage. Windkeep has been under martial rule since the death of the magistrate. I’ll take you to see Kreuger, the captain of the City Guard.” We entered through the city gates as those passing by stopped to take notice of the new arrival. It was clear from their faces that the last few weeks had been tiresome, and I was hoping my arrival wouldn’t muster any false hope. I was only a single mage, after all. I was led through the city square. Now, with a closer view of the buildings, the scars of battle on the town were visible. Broken windows were reinforced with wooden planks, several carts were turned on their sides and strategically placed as barricades, and patrolling guardsmen eyed me suspiciously as we passed by. Citizens were busily bringing in supplies, repairing downed structures, and putting out small fires. “It’s been a rough couple of weeks,” my guide explained as we entered the door of a small building. Above the door hung a carved wooden sign, picturing a dark, lifeless tree surrounded by gold lettering. The sign read: The Black Oak Inn. “The people are worried the town defenses are going to be overrun by the Scarlet Horde. There is talk about abandoning the village. Some have left already.” Entering the inn, I could tell the first floor normally served as the local pub, but today it was headquarters to the city defense force. A muscular man with dark hair, thick war armor, and an expensive-looking sword at his belt, stood at the bar. He spoke with several young guards. Based on his tone of authority, my intuition told me this was Krueger. “How long has it been since the scouting party left?” Krueger asked his officer. “Two days ago,” the young guard nervously replied. “It was only an eight hour mission at most. They should have reported back yesterday. Shall I organize a search party, Captain?” “No,” Krueger paused, noticing my entrance. “They are lost or the Horde found them. Either way, I can’t spare the men. Return to your post and shore up the southern defenses. Dismissed.” “Yes sir,” the guard said grimly as he led the other officers out of the inn. This left Krueger, myself, and my guard escort alone in the inn’s tavern. “What have we here, Bigsley?” Krueger asked. “This is Conrad,” the guard explained. “He entered from the eastern gate. Claims to be from Belgarath, sir…from the wizard’s academy?” “You’re a mage? Why have you come to Oak Dale?” Krueger investigated. I could tell from his tone that his pessimism was winning the battle against his optimism. “To be honest,” I replied, “I had no knowledge of your current situation. Ironically, I came to Windkeep for the solitude, and the peace and quiet. Ideal conditions for the study of magic.” “I can assure you,” Krueger interrupted, “there is no peace here. The Horde attacks randomly, sometimes only to set fires to our village walls and buildings. Our guards have been able to force them back into the woods so far, but our numbers have dwindled over time, and it seems like the Horde’s have been increasing. And I’m sure you’ve heard about the death of our magistrate…” “Yes,” I said. “Have you requested aid from other provinces?” “We are so remote, here,” he explained. “Scouting parties never return and convoys are attacked and forced to retreat back into the city. I’m afraid if this goes on much longer, I’ll have to order the evacuation of Windkeep.” I took a moment to consider my options. I could head back the way I came and leave these people to their own problems, or I could help them fight the Scarlet Horde. When I left Belgarath, I was determined to make Windkeep my home, and if I’ve learned anything about myself over the years, it’s that I don’t get ideas out of my head easily. “I’d like to assist in the fight,” I said abruptly, before I could talk myself out of it. “The addition of a magic wielder to our forces will be a great benefit, Conrad. Welcome to the Windkeep City Guard,” Krueger said with a smile, as he vigorously grabbed my hand and shook it. These people were more desperate than I thought. To be continued…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windkeep - Part 1: The Arrival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/17/windkeep001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windkeep - Part 1: The Arrival" /><published>2018-12-17T16:58:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-17T16:58:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/17/windkeep001</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windkeepseries/2018/12/17/windkeep001.html">&lt;p&gt;After days of narrow, rocky mountain trails, the sight of the wide dirt pathway leading into the forested valley was certainly a welcome one. Although visibility will be reduced by the thick foliage of the forest, food and shelter will be in far larger supply than it was back on the trails of the barren mountain. I looked back at the solid mass of rock in disgust. With my supplies nearly gone, it took me just shy of a week to traverse the rocky null which the locals call “Mount Baldy”…and for good reason. The prospect of spending another night choking down stale bread certainly put a spring in my step this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued down the trail and pulled out my map which was sold to me by a street vendor only weeks before. The map was crude and poorly labeled, but the scale of the pathways seemed to be accurate. The vendor had shown me on the map that it would take about six days to scale the mountain. Indeed, in six days I was on the other side. I suppose it was a good deal considering it only set me back two silver pieces, about the cost of a simple dagger. According to the map, the next landmark along this trail is the town, and my planned destination, of Windkeep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windkeep is supposed to be a sparsely populated, remote location; the perfect home of study for a recently graduated mage. With a small marketplace, Windkeep should be able to keep me supplied with all of the required wizarding components while providing me the room and freedom to perfect my spells. It’s common knowledge in this region that wizards devote years of personal study and reflection to become masters of magic, so the arrival of a nomadic mage should come as no surprise to the people of Windkeep. Heck, they may even be glad to have someone handy with magic around for emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rustle in the bushes snaps me back from my mental illustrations of Windkeep and I instinctively shove the map back in its pocket to free my hands. Fighters have their broad swords, rogues have their daggers, rangers have their bows, and wizards have their hands. I mentally prepare a defensive spell as a man in leather armor steps out of a bush and into the middle of the path. As soon as he steps out, I begin to size him up: a large wooded staff in one hand, a dagger sheathed on his belt and a ruffled appearance that makes me doubt he’s seen a bath any time recently. I can tell he’s a thief before he even opens his mouth and if that’s the case, there are likely more waiting nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello lonely traveler!” He shouts jubilantly, perhaps some weak attempt to throw me off-guard. “What brings you to travel these parts of Oakdale?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flex my fingers and stand my ground firmly, his words removing any doubt that this is indeed a robbery. I can feel the warm, tingling power of my defensive spell resonating in my left hand, so I mentally prepare an attack spell with my right. Hopefully there isn’t an army of thieves hiding in the surrounding foliage. I am only one wizard, after all. Once the spell is prepared, I respond to the inquiry, “I’m nothing but an adventurer down on his luck seeking new opportunity in Windkeep. Who wants to know?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew no story I gave would deter these robbers from carrying out their plan, so I hardly devoted any mental resources into formulating a believable story. The thief stared at me hard for a moment and almost seemed taken aback at my pathetic attempt to explain my existence. It almost seemed as if he were reconsidering going through with his plan. Unfortunately though, his greed soon overwhelmed reason and he made his demand, “My name is Jesup, I own this road and you appear to be trespassing. However, fifty silver pieces would certainly be enough to finance your passage through my lands.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as he finished, an arrow thwacked into the ground several feet in front of me. I made sure to make a note of which tree it was shot from. “I assure you that paying the toll will be in your best interest,” the thief said with a smile, as he lifted his wooden staff and began to walk towards me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have no intention of paying the toll,” I said as I released the energy stored in my left hand. There was a bright flash and my body was surrounded with magical energy. Another arrow whistled through the air and shattered into pieces, mere inches from my chest. My mage shield should hold for several more minutes, but I wasn’t going to give the archer another chance. I raised my right arm, flicked a finger and a small missile of flame shot from my fingertip. The flaming missile impacted within the branches of the targeted tree, which instantly burst into flames. The thief on the pathway, Jesup, turned his attention just in time to see his screaming partner leap from the tree in a ball of fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distraction was long enough for me to cast a detect spell. As expected, I could suddenly feel the life of Jesup flowing through me and, to a lesser extent, the fading life of his partner who lay motionless at the base of the flaming tree. I couldn’t feel the presence of any other significant life, so I felt confident this was a two-man job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesup, after seeing the flaming debris that was once his partner in crime, briefly turned to look at me and then shot off running into the forest. “Wait, you forgot your silver!” I yelled after him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flames in the tree began to die down and I approached the now deceased archer. Retrieving a vile of blue willow oil from my bag, I poured it onto the body and began to cast a revival spell. Revival spells are known to few wizards and aren’t even taught at the Mage Institution. Luckily I was fortunate enough to befriend one of the professors who taught me extra spells in his spare time. That particular fact is especially lucky for this thief who suddenly sits up, gasping for air. He slowly manages to catch his breath and looks up at me. Recognition flashes across his face and he jumps up screaming and running into the forest half-naked, his tattered, burnt clothing trailing behind him. “Not even a thank you,” I grumble to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take note that he runs in the same direction as Jesup, so I postulate there must be an encampment or fort in that direction. I decide I’ll report this incident to the Windkeep magistrate, so they can handle the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The encounter is over as quick as it began and I once again find myself back on the road towards Windkeep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To be continued…&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">After days of narrow, rocky mountain trails, the sight of the wide dirt pathway leading into the forested valley was certainly a welcome one. Although visibility will be reduced by the thick foliage of the forest, food and shelter will be in far larger supply than it was back on the trails of the barren mountain. I looked back at the solid mass of rock in disgust. With my supplies nearly gone, it took me just shy of a week to traverse the rocky null which the locals call “Mount Baldy”…and for good reason. The prospect of spending another night choking down stale bread certainly put a spring in my step this morning. I continued down the trail and pulled out my map which was sold to me by a street vendor only weeks before. The map was crude and poorly labeled, but the scale of the pathways seemed to be accurate. The vendor had shown me on the map that it would take about six days to scale the mountain. Indeed, in six days I was on the other side. I suppose it was a good deal considering it only set me back two silver pieces, about the cost of a simple dagger. According to the map, the next landmark along this trail is the town, and my planned destination, of Windkeep. Windkeep is supposed to be a sparsely populated, remote location; the perfect home of study for a recently graduated mage. With a small marketplace, Windkeep should be able to keep me supplied with all of the required wizarding components while providing me the room and freedom to perfect my spells. It’s common knowledge in this region that wizards devote years of personal study and reflection to become masters of magic, so the arrival of a nomadic mage should come as no surprise to the people of Windkeep. Heck, they may even be glad to have someone handy with magic around for emergencies. A rustle in the bushes snaps me back from my mental illustrations of Windkeep and I instinctively shove the map back in its pocket to free my hands. Fighters have their broad swords, rogues have their daggers, rangers have their bows, and wizards have their hands. I mentally prepare a defensive spell as a man in leather armor steps out of a bush and into the middle of the path. As soon as he steps out, I begin to size him up: a large wooded staff in one hand, a dagger sheathed on his belt and a ruffled appearance that makes me doubt he’s seen a bath any time recently. I can tell he’s a thief before he even opens his mouth and if that’s the case, there are likely more waiting nearby. “Hello lonely traveler!” He shouts jubilantly, perhaps some weak attempt to throw me off-guard. “What brings you to travel these parts of Oakdale?” I flex my fingers and stand my ground firmly, his words removing any doubt that this is indeed a robbery. I can feel the warm, tingling power of my defensive spell resonating in my left hand, so I mentally prepare an attack spell with my right. Hopefully there isn’t an army of thieves hiding in the surrounding foliage. I am only one wizard, after all. Once the spell is prepared, I respond to the inquiry, “I’m nothing but an adventurer down on his luck seeking new opportunity in Windkeep. Who wants to know?” I knew no story I gave would deter these robbers from carrying out their plan, so I hardly devoted any mental resources into formulating a believable story. The thief stared at me hard for a moment and almost seemed taken aback at my pathetic attempt to explain my existence. It almost seemed as if he were reconsidering going through with his plan. Unfortunately though, his greed soon overwhelmed reason and he made his demand, “My name is Jesup, I own this road and you appear to be trespassing. However, fifty silver pieces would certainly be enough to finance your passage through my lands.” Just as he finished, an arrow thwacked into the ground several feet in front of me. I made sure to make a note of which tree it was shot from. “I assure you that paying the toll will be in your best interest,” the thief said with a smile, as he lifted his wooden staff and began to walk towards me. “I have no intention of paying the toll,” I said as I released the energy stored in my left hand. There was a bright flash and my body was surrounded with magical energy. Another arrow whistled through the air and shattered into pieces, mere inches from my chest. My mage shield should hold for several more minutes, but I wasn’t going to give the archer another chance. I raised my right arm, flicked a finger and a small missile of flame shot from my fingertip. The flaming missile impacted within the branches of the targeted tree, which instantly burst into flames. The thief on the pathway, Jesup, turned his attention just in time to see his screaming partner leap from the tree in a ball of fire. This distraction was long enough for me to cast a detect spell. As expected, I could suddenly feel the life of Jesup flowing through me and, to a lesser extent, the fading life of his partner who lay motionless at the base of the flaming tree. I couldn’t feel the presence of any other significant life, so I felt confident this was a two-man job. Jesup, after seeing the flaming debris that was once his partner in crime, briefly turned to look at me and then shot off running into the forest. “Wait, you forgot your silver!” I yelled after him. The flames in the tree began to die down and I approached the now deceased archer. Retrieving a vile of blue willow oil from my bag, I poured it onto the body and began to cast a revival spell. Revival spells are known to few wizards and aren’t even taught at the Mage Institution. Luckily I was fortunate enough to befriend one of the professors who taught me extra spells in his spare time. That particular fact is especially lucky for this thief who suddenly sits up, gasping for air. He slowly manages to catch his breath and looks up at me. Recognition flashes across his face and he jumps up screaming and running into the forest half-naked, his tattered, burnt clothing trailing behind him. “Not even a thank you,” I grumble to myself. I take note that he runs in the same direction as Jesup, so I postulate there must be an encampment or fort in that direction. I decide I’ll report this incident to the Windkeep magistrate, so they can handle the situation. The encounter is over as quick as it began and I once again find myself back on the road towards Windkeep. To be continued…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Things I Learned From Not Drinking For 12 Weeks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/self-improvement/2018/12/14/whatilearnedfrom12weeksofnotdrinking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Things I Learned From Not Drinking For 12 Weeks" /><published>2018-12-14T08:19:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-14T08:19:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/self-improvement/2018/12/14/whatilearnedfrom12weeksofnotdrinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/self-improvement/2018/12/14/whatilearnedfrom12weeksofnotdrinking.html">&lt;p&gt;I like to look at life’s challenges as opportunities. I’ve had a fungal infection on my small toenail on my right foot for years, and this year I made it one of my goals to take care of it. The issue really had no impact on my life, other than a thick, yellow toenail on my smallest toe. I had genetically inherited the proclivity to catch this kind of nail fungus from my dad, who had major problems with nail fungus all his life. Frankly, I’m lucky I don’t have bigger issues with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the doctor’s recommendation for treatment was to begin a regiment of anti-fungal medication, that I would need to take daily for 12 weeks. The downside? This medication is very hard on the liver, so I would not be able to drink for the entire window of treatment. I surprised myself to find I was kind of excited about the prospect, the excuse &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to this, I wouldn’t have called my drinking habits &lt;i&gt;heavy&lt;/i&gt;, but I wouldn’t have called them &lt;i&gt;healthy&lt;/i&gt; either. I’d probably estimate 5-10 drinks per week, on average. Now that I put a number on it, it does seem like a lot. I’d typically have at least one drink a night, and more on the weekends. At least one weekend night, I’d probably have 3-5 drinks. Twelve weeks was certainly the longest period I’ve gone without drinking in the last 20-ish years (since I was 21).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I learn over these 12 weeks? Let’s find out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;strong&gt;It was harder than I thought.&lt;/strong&gt; Drinking is ingrained in our society and some friendships are even based on it. It certainly was a big part of my life, particularly on the weekends. Quite a few of our group activities were literally “to drink”. We’d go wine tasting, bar hopping, or visit breweries. Of course, socializing with friends was the real activity here, but there are healthier ways to accomplish that. I went on a work trip during this period, and during evening get-togethers, attendees would ask me what was wrong with me like I was a terminally ill patient, or shove drinks in my face. Unfortunately, with drinking off the table, time with friends certainly diminished, and when we did get together, my not drinking was a common topic of conversation, as we made plans for the future for my eventual return back to the drinking-world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the habitual side, the first few weeks were difficult, but not oppressive. There were times in the evenings when I’d really crave a beer, or during board game nights when I’d normally always be drinking. For some reason, probably because I’m a masochist, I made sure to challenge myself by leaving the fridge fully stocked with beer (I wouldn’t recommend this for other people though). After 3 weeks or so, the habit went away, and the urge for the evening drink went away. I did still crave a drink (and still do) during board game nights, but I just replaced beer with kombucha or flavored sparkling water, and I was fine. My advice for ending a bad habit would be to replace it with a good habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;strong&gt;Drinking has its place.&lt;/strong&gt; Although I eventually came to the conclusion that drinking had too big a place in my life, there certainly is still a place for it. Drinking, on occasion, can strengthen bonds between friends in ways that cannot be done sober. Although drinking is a stress in itself, it can help to relieve stresses in other areas of your life, by allowing you to forget your cares for the night. The danger here, is the addictive nature of constantly needing to forget your cares. If you find you need to constantly drink to be happy, alcohol isn’t for you. You need to seek help, or make other significant changes in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;strong&gt;My mood was much more stable.&lt;/strong&gt; After the first few weeks, my mood stabilized quite a bit. The constant highs and lows were gone, and I felt a much more consistent feeling of contentment. I’m not really sure why, but I attribute this to my body chemistry stabilizing from no longer processing alcohol, keeping better hydration, and getting better sleep. Speaking of which…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;strong&gt;Sleep has noticeably improved.&lt;/strong&gt; I immediately found I was able to sleep through the night easier, and feel more refreshed when waking. Anything more than two drinks, typically meant I would wake in the middle of the night and have trouble going back to sleep. Those days are essentially gone. If you have sleep issues, cut out alcohol and see what happens. Even if you don’t have sleep issues, experiment with a couple weeks without alcohol and see if you notice a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;strong&gt;Overall I don’t feel all that different.&lt;/strong&gt; Other than what I’ve previously mentioned, I don’t really feel all that significantly different, both physically and psychologically. I still have my days when I feel great, and occasional days when I feel ‘meh’. In comparison, I feel significantly better after a week of fasting, so for my body, diet is more important than whether or not I drink. When hanging out with friends, I still had fun and never felt like I needed to drink to participate socially. The thought then occurred to me, if I don’t feel that different, why do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &lt;strong&gt;Drinking is expensive.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing a little math, assuming a ball-park of $3 per drink, with an average of eight drinks per week, comes out to a conservatively low number of $100 per month. I bet I spent way more a month than that, since quite often we’d be drinking $8 brewery beers. This one speaks for itself, I gave myself a significant income boost by not drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, now that I can drink again, what are my habits like today?&lt;/strong&gt; 
It’s been over a month since I’ve completed my medication regiment, and I’ve made some interesting observations. First, I no longer enjoy the taste of beer (as much). I used to love the hoppy IPAs, but now they no longer seem appetizing. However, my tastes have increased significantly for red wine, particularly cabernet. I’m not really sure how to explain this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I don’t really enjoy drinking anymore. In social settings, I really got used to having all my wits about me, having a clear mind, and having full control of my physical faculties. After a few drinks, I lose these characteristics, and I take less enjoyment from interactions…as if I’m limited in some way (which I am). Turns out, I like being clear headed. I’m very pleased with this result, as I had feared my return to drinking might result in worse habits than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I do still drink on occasion, but the amount has significantly reduced. I almost never have more than two drinks on a single day, and that’s once a week at most. If I have 3-4 drinks in a given week, that’s a lot of drinks for me. The daily urge to drink I had previously no longer exists. If you’re concerned about your drinking habits, maybe a break will work for you too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh, one final note.&lt;/strong&gt; Over the twelve week period, I lost around 10 pounds; however, I did couple this experiment with a calorie reduction, and also switched my diet to Ketogenic, so I can’t firmly conclude ‘not drinking’ was a factor in weight loss. Common sense though, would suggest that it can’t hurt!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">I like to look at life’s challenges as opportunities. I’ve had a fungal infection on my small toenail on my right foot for years, and this year I made it one of my goals to take care of it. The issue really had no impact on my life, other than a thick, yellow toenail on my smallest toe. I had genetically inherited the proclivity to catch this kind of nail fungus from my dad, who had major problems with nail fungus all his life. Frankly, I’m lucky I don’t have bigger issues with it. Anyway, the doctor’s recommendation for treatment was to begin a regiment of anti-fungal medication, that I would need to take daily for 12 weeks. The downside? This medication is very hard on the liver, so I would not be able to drink for the entire window of treatment. I surprised myself to find I was kind of excited about the prospect, the excuse not to drink. Prior to this, I wouldn’t have called my drinking habits heavy, but I wouldn’t have called them healthy either. I’d probably estimate 5-10 drinks per week, on average. Now that I put a number on it, it does seem like a lot. I’d typically have at least one drink a night, and more on the weekends. At least one weekend night, I’d probably have 3-5 drinks. Twelve weeks was certainly the longest period I’ve gone without drinking in the last 20-ish years (since I was 21). So what did I learn over these 12 weeks? Let’s find out: 1) It was harder than I thought. Drinking is ingrained in our society and some friendships are even based on it. It certainly was a big part of my life, particularly on the weekends. Quite a few of our group activities were literally “to drink”. We’d go wine tasting, bar hopping, or visit breweries. Of course, socializing with friends was the real activity here, but there are healthier ways to accomplish that. I went on a work trip during this period, and during evening get-togethers, attendees would ask me what was wrong with me like I was a terminally ill patient, or shove drinks in my face. Unfortunately, with drinking off the table, time with friends certainly diminished, and when we did get together, my not drinking was a common topic of conversation, as we made plans for the future for my eventual return back to the drinking-world. On the habitual side, the first few weeks were difficult, but not oppressive. There were times in the evenings when I’d really crave a beer, or during board game nights when I’d normally always be drinking. For some reason, probably because I’m a masochist, I made sure to challenge myself by leaving the fridge fully stocked with beer (I wouldn’t recommend this for other people though). After 3 weeks or so, the habit went away, and the urge for the evening drink went away. I did still crave a drink (and still do) during board game nights, but I just replaced beer with kombucha or flavored sparkling water, and I was fine. My advice for ending a bad habit would be to replace it with a good habit. 2) Drinking has its place. Although I eventually came to the conclusion that drinking had too big a place in my life, there certainly is still a place for it. Drinking, on occasion, can strengthen bonds between friends in ways that cannot be done sober. Although drinking is a stress in itself, it can help to relieve stresses in other areas of your life, by allowing you to forget your cares for the night. The danger here, is the addictive nature of constantly needing to forget your cares. If you find you need to constantly drink to be happy, alcohol isn’t for you. You need to seek help, or make other significant changes in your life. 3) My mood was much more stable. After the first few weeks, my mood stabilized quite a bit. The constant highs and lows were gone, and I felt a much more consistent feeling of contentment. I’m not really sure why, but I attribute this to my body chemistry stabilizing from no longer processing alcohol, keeping better hydration, and getting better sleep. Speaking of which… 4) Sleep has noticeably improved. I immediately found I was able to sleep through the night easier, and feel more refreshed when waking. Anything more than two drinks, typically meant I would wake in the middle of the night and have trouble going back to sleep. Those days are essentially gone. If you have sleep issues, cut out alcohol and see what happens. Even if you don’t have sleep issues, experiment with a couple weeks without alcohol and see if you notice a difference. 5) Overall I don’t feel all that different. Other than what I’ve previously mentioned, I don’t really feel all that significantly different, both physically and psychologically. I still have my days when I feel great, and occasional days when I feel ‘meh’. In comparison, I feel significantly better after a week of fasting, so for my body, diet is more important than whether or not I drink. When hanging out with friends, I still had fun and never felt like I needed to drink to participate socially. The thought then occurred to me, if I don’t feel that different, why do it? 6) Drinking is expensive. Doing a little math, assuming a ball-park of $3 per drink, with an average of eight drinks per week, comes out to a conservatively low number of $100 per month. I bet I spent way more a month than that, since quite often we’d be drinking $8 brewery beers. This one speaks for itself, I gave myself a significant income boost by not drinking. So, now that I can drink again, what are my habits like today? It’s been over a month since I’ve completed my medication regiment, and I’ve made some interesting observations. First, I no longer enjoy the taste of beer (as much). I used to love the hoppy IPAs, but now they no longer seem appetizing. However, my tastes have increased significantly for red wine, particularly cabernet. I’m not really sure how to explain this change. Second, I don’t really enjoy drinking anymore. In social settings, I really got used to having all my wits about me, having a clear mind, and having full control of my physical faculties. After a few drinks, I lose these characteristics, and I take less enjoyment from interactions…as if I’m limited in some way (which I am). Turns out, I like being clear headed. I’m very pleased with this result, as I had feared my return to drinking might result in worse habits than before. Finally, I do still drink on occasion, but the amount has significantly reduced. I almost never have more than two drinks on a single day, and that’s once a week at most. If I have 3-4 drinks in a given week, that’s a lot of drinks for me. The daily urge to drink I had previously no longer exists. If you’re concerned about your drinking habits, maybe a break will work for you too! Oh, one final note. Over the twelve week period, I lost around 10 pounds; however, I did couple this experiment with a calorie reduction, and also switched my diet to Ketogenic, so I can’t firmly conclude ‘not drinking’ was a factor in weight loss. Common sense though, would suggest that it can’t hurt!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So, what’s this site all about?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/11/whatsthissiteallabout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, what's this site all about?" /><published>2018-12-11T11:34:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-11T11:34:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/11/whatsthissiteallabout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about/2018/12/11/whatsthissiteallabout.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been an IT guy for two decades, and have two degrees in computer science related fields. During my time working as an “IT guy” and pursuing my education, I’ve always taken an interest in reading and telling stories. I’m a huge board gamer, and the thing I love most about board games are the stories they help you experience with your friends. RPG-style games are a huge hit with my group, and I’ve often found myself writing my own campaign scenarios and even designing my own customized game rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site will be my white-board of writing ideas, short-stories, and maybe even a few novel length stories. I’m not sure what this will evolve to, but maybe one day this will be the seed that will grow into something larger than a simple blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, I’m not good at writing. Hopefully, over time, this site will help to change that. No one started out &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; at anything. Practice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Watson</name><email>tenuous.io@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’ve been an IT guy for two decades, and have two degrees in computer science related fields. During my time working as an “IT guy” and pursuing my education, I’ve always taken an interest in reading and telling stories. I’m a huge board gamer, and the thing I love most about board games are the stories they help you experience with your friends. RPG-style games are a huge hit with my group, and I’ve often found myself writing my own campaign scenarios and even designing my own customized game rules. This site will be my white-board of writing ideas, short-stories, and maybe even a few novel length stories. I’m not sure what this will evolve to, but maybe one day this will be the seed that will grow into something larger than a simple blog. I’ll admit, I’m not good at writing. Hopefully, over time, this site will help to change that. No one started out great at anything. Practice.</summary></entry></feed>